...
My name is Laura Eley, second in command
of the starship Cassiopia.
With Earth dying, we looked to the stars
for a new home.
Only one held promise, Taoi F. Our
objective, survey the planet from orbit
to prepare for the arrival of our
sisterhip, the colony vessel Andromeda.
Humanity's future depended on us.
Or so we thought.
...
I don't recognize
his face.
I don't wantize
my gaze.
...
Will I be here forever?
Can't keep my thoughts together.
My head's on fire on fire.
My hands on fire on fire.
...
&gt;&gt; Sims.
Sims. What was that?
...
Carter,
&gt;&gt; are you not remotely alarmed?
&gt;&gt; Not yet. Are you?
&gt;&gt; It sounded like a hull impact.
...
&gt;&gt; Chances are pretty low.
&gt;&gt; Low, but not zero.
...
&gt;&gt; 100 bucks says it's another Java bean
incident.
&gt;&gt; That was one time.
&gt;&gt; One time. You are never going to live
down.
...
&gt;&gt; Breach detected. Tech two.
&gt;&gt; That's not good.
&gt;&gt; Complex.
&gt;&gt; Port side. This deck. The whole area has
been locked down and sealed.
&gt;&gt; Should we wait the others?
&gt;&gt; We're only 72 hours from orbit. Let's
stick to procedure and take a look
ourselves.
&gt;&gt; Should we consult the Oracle?
...
You're right. It would be smart to get
further data before taking action.
&gt;&gt; Roundabout way of saying good idea,
Sims, but I'll take it.
&gt;&gt; Okay, lead the way.
...
Authorization failed. Additional crew
login required.
&gt;&gt; Oh, come on, Carter. You need to log
into your utility strap.
...
Got it.
&gt;&gt; Let's get this door open.
&gt;&gt; Hang on. Let me just test. It's working.
...
Lock down lifted.
&gt;&gt; King to C1.
&gt;&gt; Okay.
...
Knight to E2. Check.
&gt;&gt; King to B1.
&gt;&gt; Knight follows. Check.
...
Good evening, Carter.
&gt;&gt; Good evening, Oracle. I would like a
full situation report.
A meteorite has penetrated my outer
hall, puncturing through to the
maintenance facilities on deck 4.
...
I have disabled systems across the ship
to conserve power and isolate damage.
...
&gt;&gt; Can you deal with this? Oracle,
&gt;&gt; automated repairs have failed. Damage
containment is now my priority.
When were you going to tell us this?
&gt;&gt; I'm telling you now, Sims.
&gt;&gt; Is our mission at risk?
&gt;&gt; My life support systems are intact, but
I advise a systems reboot to provide an
accurate damage report.
&gt;&gt; Systems reboot.
Wouldn't that make it harder for us to
deal with the breach?
&gt;&gt; I don't know, Sims, but without a
reboot, further damage could occur.
...
Delay the reboot. Repairing the breach
is our immediate priority. One problem
at a time.
&gt;&gt; Understood.
...
The damage must be shorting the ship's
electronics.
&gt;&gt; Should we fix it?
&gt;&gt; We need to inspect the hull damage
first.
Here, help me open it.
...
The lights are out.
&gt;&gt; I hadn't noticed.
&gt;&gt; Must have been a power surge.
...
The whole area is on lockdown. We're not
getting through here.
&gt;&gt; Convenient.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; The lockdown should be hardwired to a
nearby terminal. Open your scanner. See
what comes up.
...
&gt;&gt; Can you see the live wire?
Uh-huh.
&gt;&gt; Follow it through to the terminal.
...
What do you see?
&gt;&gt; A butterfly.
&gt;&gt; Beauty.
&gt;&gt; What about this?
&gt;&gt; A secret handshake.
&gt;&gt; A fortress.
&gt;&gt; And this?
&gt;&gt; I don't know.
&gt;&gt; I see
potential. History in the making.
&gt;&gt; Secrets of the universe.
&gt;&gt; I see whatever we want it to be.
Corinth,
where humanity comes first.
...
There it is.
Huh.
Looks like the breach webbing hasn't
fired.
&gt;&gt; Figures.
We've got to repair that breach. Looks
like the only way to override the
sealant system now is from outside the
hull.
...
&gt;&gt; Not really in the mood for a walk.
&gt;&gt; It's our only option. What would
Stafford say?
&gt;&gt; Never forget where you started.
&gt;&gt; Would you look at that?
gets me every time.
&gt;&gt; Come on, Galileo.
&gt;&gt; We've earned a little holiday, haven't
we?
...
&gt;&gt; King to C1.
&gt;&gt; You know, I'm trying so hard not to fall
over that I feel like I actually might
fall over.
&gt;&gt; Please don't do that. But don't even say
that.
&gt;&gt; Still thinking it.
&gt;&gt; We should probably check the FDL
antenna. Roger that. Console's just
here.
...
Looks good to me.
Optical terminal is intact.
Transmission speed is dipped, but should
course correct soon.
Want to run some diagnostics just to be
sure.
Let me just check the message logs.
Hey, baby.
We miss you already, and we wanted to
tell you how proud of you we both are.
What you're doing is I know you had
second thoughts, but
it's the right thing. The future is all
that matters to us now. The future with
you.
Good luck among the stars.
&gt;&gt; Good luck, Daddy.
&gt;&gt; Good luck.
How many times have you watched that
one?
&gt;&gt; I lost count last Christmas.
&gt;&gt; We're expecting a new batch in a few
days when the rest of the crew wakes up.
We've waited long enough.
&gt;&gt; Antenna's fully functional. That's good
news for the mission.
&gt;&gt; Can you imagine Stafford's face if we
woke up to mission failure?
&gt;&gt; I'm not angry, just disappointed.
&gt;&gt; Oh man.
Impact
...
must have boiled the water and caused a
rupture.
&gt;&gt; Doesn't look too bad.
&gt;&gt; Doesn't look too good either.
&gt;&gt; If we fix the sealant system, it should
fix that, too.
&gt;&gt; Good point. Let's keep moving.
...
What a mess.
&gt;&gt; Understatement of the year.
...
&gt;&gt; What is that?
&gt;&gt; Coolant. Maybe
...
That did the job.
Can we go home now?
&gt;&gt; Agreed. Back to the airlock.
...
Hard to believe.
Things are going to change around here
for us. That's for sure.
&gt;&gt; Stop moving. Live in the moment like me.
Each day, one step at a time.
...
&gt;&gt; You always find a way to see the bright
side.
&gt;&gt; Mom taught me that. You can't always
control what happens, but you can
control how you react to it. I can
control the muscles in my face, so I use
them to smile.
&gt;&gt; It's hard to though sometimes.
&gt;&gt; That's why I try to focus on the now.
The past isn't worth wasting a frown on.
&gt;&gt; Everything I do,
I do it for my daughter's future.
What we're doing here is a vital step
into a new tomorrow for everyone.
&gt;&gt; Okay, now you are sounding like one of
William's training videos.
&gt;&gt; We're doing something incredible. Sims,
&gt;&gt; when everyone's up, you think they'll
relegate us to coffee making?
&gt;&gt; Knowing Williams, I wouldn't doubt it.
&gt;&gt; Time doesn't have the same meaning out
here. Those
guys close their eyes for a night's
sleep
and they wake up refreshed like these
four years meant nothing.
&gt;&gt; God, I'm older than Cernin now.
&gt;&gt; You know, he once told me this.
&gt;&gt; Sims,
&gt;&gt; helper, help me.
&gt;&gt; Use your thruster now.
...
&gt;&gt; We're okay. We're okay.
&gt;&gt; I am so sorry.
&gt;&gt; No, I'm just glad.
I thought,
"Thank God." Yeah.
...
Should we tell Earth?
&gt;&gt; We can handle this.
&gt;&gt; Well, should we at least wait? Cernin,
&gt;&gt; we stick to protocol. Run diagnostics
first, then we can decide what to do
after that. Sure.
...
&gt;&gt; Years of work on that bonsai
&gt;&gt; gone.
&gt;&gt; With only one branch. I'm sure we can
fix it.
&gt;&gt; You don't know much about horty culture,
do you?
&gt;&gt; Hear me out. Remember when I was reading
fracture and repair and there was that
chapter on
&gt;&gt; Ginsugi? Oh, yes. I remember it.
&gt;&gt; Right. Why not apply it here? Take
what's broken and honor its faults.
Highlight them even.
&gt;&gt; That's wonderful. Except I'm pretty sure
Kugi is for pottery, not plants.
You can still apply the mindset celebr
...
Sims
is dead.
...
Okay, Sims, that is not funny. I don't
appreciate the joke.
...
Sims,
are are you okay?
You can talk to me.
I know it's been tough for you out here.
But I thought you were past this.
...
&gt;&gt; Never
forget
why.
...
It's hard to let go. Earth is the only
home we've known.
&gt;&gt; But the truth is, our home is dying. I
don't
&gt;&gt; want to hurt you.
&gt;&gt; We need to let go.
an app.
...
My mom is dead.
Everyone is dead.
...
Where are you, man? I don't want to hurt
you.
...
&gt;&gt; Arthur,
I'm scared.
...
My mom is dead.
&gt;&gt; Everyone is dead.
...
&gt;&gt; Schedule systems reboot initiated.
Please stand by. [__] [__] [__]
...
Oh my god.
This is Thomas Carter, 48 hours from
flight crew. Wake up. Something's wrong
with Sims. I I don't know. She She
attacked me. I Oh, God. She's trying to
kill me.
We were repairing an impact to the hull.
We separated to repair different areas
of the ship, but then
...
We have always questioned whether we're
alone in the universe.
It's only when we come face to face with
death that we get our answer.
However connected the universe may be,
in the end
we all die alone.
...
I wasn't sure you'd be here.
&gt;&gt; I wouldn't miss it for the world.
...
&gt;&gt; Curfew's starting early tonight. The Met
says there's a storm building over the
Atlantic. Could be dark for a few days.
That shouldn't affect the launch though.
&gt;&gt; Sometimes you look just like him, you
know.
&gt;&gt; That's called genetics.
&gt;&gt; No, it's more than that.
&gt;&gt; It's the way you carry yourself
as a confidence.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, you're talking about my swagger.
...
&gt;&gt; It still doesn't feel real sometimes.
Dad was always gone for years on a
mission. I'm almost waiting for him to
walk back through the door.
&gt;&gt; I know. Every time I say your name, I'm
taken right back to those first missions
with him. Oh,
&gt;&gt; I'm sorry.
&gt;&gt; There's nothing to be sorry for.
It's nice to remember him.
...
&gt;&gt; I can't stop thinking about him,
&gt;&gt; especially now.
If he was in our position,
what would he do?
&gt;&gt; I have wondered that myself.
...
Have you taken the time to really think
it through?
&gt;&gt; I understand your concerns, young, but
what have we really got to lose?
You know, I look at you now and I see
that kid flying wild into the sun.
&gt;&gt; That was a long time ago
&gt;&gt; when your father and I were on Mars and
we lost that CO2 tank.
...
Yeah. He never once panicked. Just
treated it like any other job we needed
to do. Calm, composed.
I remember it like it was yesterday.
Yeah. I asked him how he could be so
relaxed and he just turned to me and he
said,
&gt;&gt; "Never forget why you started.
&gt;&gt; Never forget why you started.
...
to Bill
to Dad.
...
BP20 over 70,
heart rate 72,
temperature 97.2.
...
&gt;&gt; Good morning, T2.
&gt;&gt; Take it easy. You'll feel groggy for a
while.
&gt;&gt; No [__]
&gt;&gt; Oxygen saturation 95%.
Respiration nominal.
Look up.
...
Pupils equal. Round and alert.
Subjects fully conscious.
Good morning, young
...
&gt;&gt; Carter and Sims. Shouldn't they be here?
&gt;&gt; Well, that is standard procedure,
&gt;&gt; but this isn't a standard situation.
&gt;&gt; Sims,
&gt;&gt; what's wrong?
&gt;&gt; Yuri,
&gt;&gt; Stafford and I were woken up
automatically by the ship.
&gt;&gt; He's trying to reach the sleep
technicians now.
&gt;&gt; Sims.
&gt;&gt; So, wake up's on me.
&gt;&gt; Yuri,
...
&gt;&gt; what's going on? Sadly,
&gt;&gt; we're reading multiple system crashes.
I've been trying to establish why.
...
&gt;&gt; Thanks.
Where are we?
&gt;&gt; Right where we're supposed to be. Within
range of the marker and decelerating for
orbit.
...
Carter Zms,
you read
...
&gt;&gt; legend.
&gt;&gt; Simple pleasures, huh?
&gt;&gt; How you feeling?
&gt;&gt; Like the hangover from hell.
...
try that.
&gt;&gt; This is Commander Stafford.
Where the hell are you two?
...
&gt;&gt; I read you, sir. We're in engineering.
The ship suffered a minor hull breach,
so we're running diagnostics and making
the necessary repairs as per protocol.
&gt;&gt; How bad are we talking?
&gt;&gt; We're still running diagnostics. Once
we're done, we'll provide a full damage
report.
&gt;&gt; Gut feeling.
&gt;&gt; Manageable. Looks like we were lucky.
&gt;&gt; Anything we need to jump on?
&gt;&gt; We're trying to establish that now.
&gt;&gt; Our orbital window is in 1 hour. Have
you made engine preparations?
No, sir. The damage from the home breach
took priority.
&gt;&gt; Understood. We'll prep the engines
ourselves.
&gt;&gt; Apologies. We weren't there to wake you,
sir.
...
&gt;&gt; Can you confirm how many of you are
awake?
&gt;&gt; Just the four flight crew.
We'll wake the others in order as
planned.
...
&gt;&gt; You okay?
&gt;&gt; Just snoozing.
&gt;&gt; Four years of sleep wasn't enough, huh?
Whenever you're ready, kiddo.
...
Rise and shine, sleeping beauty.
&gt;&gt; And to what do I owe the honor of this
royal welcome?
&gt;&gt; There's been a hole breach. Carter and
Sims are looking into it. It would
explain why our oxygen processing is
down.
&gt;&gt; That sounds bad.
&gt;&gt; Sound of control, but we're only an hour
from the marker. Young Eley, begin
engine checks in preparation for orbit.
I'll take Mitchell and we'll reboot the
CO2 scrubbers.
&gt;&gt; How about I save some oxygen and go back
to sleep.
&gt;&gt; Come on, we have jobs to do.
...
&gt;&gt; You feeling all right?
&gt;&gt; Uh, kind of weird. Feels like I went to
sleep only yesterday and now I have a
headache four years in the making.
It's like my body's going one way and my
mind's going another.
&gt;&gt; That's to be expected.
Humans weren't made for hibernation.
&gt;&gt; Science.
&gt;&gt; Make sure you take care of yourself over
the course of the mission. Body and
mind. You understand?
&gt;&gt; Well, these guns have been asleep way
too long.
&gt;&gt; Had a boy.
...
Hey, uh, meant to ask you before they
put us under, how do you feel about this
being your last mission, your grand
finale?
&gt;&gt; It's a hell of an encore.
&gt;&gt; First man exoplanetary mission. Not bad
for a commander's farewell.
...
&gt;&gt; My duty is to serve. It's all I've ever
known. I'm the luckiest commander in the
Corinth ranks with the best team I could
have asked for. There's no other crew
like us.
&gt;&gt; It's a real shame we lost Magnamera.
&gt;&gt; A damn tragedy.
What's your take on Anders? Bit of a
late replacement, huh?
You trust her?
...
I trust the current recruitment process.
If McNamar was the best, Anders is a
close second, especially given Kooper's
seal of approval.
&gt;&gt; Sure, I guess so. Eley, we're almost at
hydroponics. Head over when you're done.
...
&gt;&gt; Okay, remind me why we're here.
&gt;&gt; Because the technicians didn't do their
jobs.
&gt;&gt; You'll need to bring the reactor to full
power.
&gt;&gt; You know, I've never flown something
with a reactor this size. You aren't
worried it might pop?
They get more unstable the bigger they
are, don't they?
&gt;&gt; Don't be sensational. The texts come a
long way since Jessup Station. You'd
struggle to break this one even if you
tried.
&gt;&gt; How can you be so sure?
&gt;&gt; Because I trust the science and I trust
my [__]
...
&gt;&gt; Come on, we need to get back on
schedule.
...
The Oracle is suggesting we redirect
power from the landing systems.
Just as well, considering we're not
landing. Alternatively, we redirect
power from fire control.
...
&gt;&gt; Landing systems temporarily disabled.
&gt;&gt; There we go.
...
Just like Christmas.
That's good considering we've missed the
last few.
&gt;&gt; Thanks for the reminder.
...
&gt;&gt; Hey,
sit there long enough, you'll grow
roots.
&gt;&gt; Bite me.
...
&gt;&gt; No, it's it's good to see you taking
care of your mental health. And
&gt;&gt; engines are prepped and the power plant
is fully operational, commander. a joke.
&gt;&gt; We're ready for orbit.
&gt;&gt; Excellent.
&gt;&gt; Good work, Eisley.
&gt;&gt; What did the pilot say when he walked
into the bar?
&gt;&gt; Um, I don't know. What did the
&gt;&gt; Given the circumstances, I'd say they're
both performing well.
&gt;&gt; Aren't they just
That tree was a neat addition. It's good
to have a reminder of home.
&gt;&gt; Actually, it measurably reduces the load
on our oxygen scrubbers.
Plus, its canopy serves as an effective
dust filter.
But yes, I had a hawthorn just like it
in my garden back at home. It's actually
a cutting.
&gt;&gt; A little piece of you.
&gt;&gt; I'm glad you're with us, Eisley. This
ship is all you. You should be proud to
sail aboard it.
&gt;&gt; Of course, sir.
...
&gt;&gt; A dad joke. I must say I'm disappointed
with our sleep technicians.
&gt;&gt; I'd expected more efficiency from them.
...
&gt;&gt; You think they should have been there to
wake us?
&gt;&gt; I'd like to know why they thought the
repairs were more important.
For the record, I'd like to check their
service logs.
...
&gt;&gt; Very well. for the record.
But Eley, do remember that we're all a
long way from home.
...
&gt;&gt; You ever think what you might have been
if you weren't a pilot?
&gt;&gt; Not a chance. This has always been it
for me.
&gt;&gt; Goddamn right.
...
I could die out here.
&gt;&gt; But that is not going to happen.
&gt;&gt; No, I mean like it'd be cool.
&gt;&gt; What would you do?
&gt;&gt; Gosh, I don't know. I'd be dead.
&gt;&gt; No, I meant with my body. If I had died,
would you just pop the airlock and send
me floating out into space?
...
Company guidelines state no littering in
orbit. That definitely includes your
dead ass.
&gt;&gt; Cold blooded.
&gt;&gt; Actually, hydro, you'd make perfect
fertilizer for the shrubbery.
&gt;&gt; You know, like a back to nature kind of
thing. I could visit every night and
fill you in on the latest.
But don't go dying. just yet.
&gt;&gt; All for you, I'd go for permission.
Freeze drying.
&gt;&gt; Seriously?
&gt;&gt; Yeah, it would be kind of fun. Put you
into an airtight bag, stick you out into
negative 270°, shake you around a little
until you shatter into a million pieces.
&gt;&gt; Then, hey, presto, finally ground young.
&gt;&gt; Hey.
&gt;&gt; Wow.
&gt;&gt; For now, let's just both stay alive.
&gt;&gt; No dying intended.
Unless I actually land this [__] I'm
tossfet's
...
first dead guy.
&gt;&gt; Don't even joke about that.
&gt;&gt; What's eating you?
&gt;&gt; Sometimes I can't tell if you're joking
or just being an ass.
...
Sims.
Sims. What was that?
...
&gt;&gt; Right. Why not apply it here? Take
what's in them and honor its fault.
Highlight them even.
&gt;&gt; That's wonderful. Except I'm pretty sure
Ksuki is for pottery, not plants.
&gt;&gt; You can still apply the mindset.
Celebrate the beauty and the flaws.
...
&gt;&gt; Sorry, Commander.
Sorry, Commander. There's just too much.
&gt;&gt; Sorry, Commander. There's just too much
interference down there.
...
You are one mother.
&gt;&gt; Jesus, Stafford.
&gt;&gt; Those guys are so entranced.
&gt;&gt; The sleep technicians.
I thought I'd check their surveillance
logs and I found something weird.
Look at the time code on this one. It's
from after the impact.
They should be running repairs at that
time.
&gt;&gt; It looks odd, but the systems are
glitching all over the ship. The camera
probably crashed, but the time code kept
running.
&gt;&gt; That's an assumption.
&gt;&gt; What are you suggesting?
...
&gt;&gt; Don't you think it's odd? Is it normal
behavior to be standing still, staring
at us for hours on end?
...
What's going on?
I don't know, Eisely.
Looks like a glitch to me.
&gt;&gt; And how do you explain the missing files
just as things got abnormal?
...
&gt;&gt; We don't know how bad the systems have
been damaged. We have to consider the
facts before jumping to conclusions.
&gt;&gt; But the facts are right here on this
tape.
&gt;&gt; Commander, we're coming up to the marker
now. We need to prep the boostering
detachment.
&gt;&gt; Confirmed. Thanks, young.
...
You're the last person I need to remind
how important this mission is. I can't
have you distracted by paranoia. I need
you on point.
&gt;&gt; But sir,
&gt;&gt; what more do you want?
...
&gt;&gt; Something about this doesn't sit right
with me.
...
Have you heard from Sims?
&gt;&gt; I'll speak to them. Don't worry.
&gt;&gt; I just think it's worth getting in touch
with them directly.
&gt;&gt; I'll need all hands on deck for the
detachment,
especially my second in command.
&gt;&gt; Do you mind if I speak to Carton Sims?
&gt;&gt; I'll talk to them. Trust me.
...
&gt;&gt; Pumps are clear, so you should be good
for the burn. Unless she's hiding more
surprises up her sleeve. We've run three
test cycles now, and we're reading
nominal in all lines.
&gt;&gt; Good work. We're still experiencing
shorts in the lighting and surveillance
systems. Any ETA on a fix?
&gt;&gt; Uh, that's on Carter. He's still in the
guts doing wiring repairs.
&gt;&gt; Can you patch me through? I'd like to
hear his voice.
&gt;&gt; Sure.
&gt;&gt; The damage must be shorting the ship's
electronics.
...
&gt;&gt; Carter,
&gt;&gt; can you hear me?
&gt;&gt; Sorry, Commander. There's just too much
interference down there.
&gt;&gt; Never mind. Just make sure he's well
clear of there before we engage the
breaking burn. Take care, Sims.
...
Status report.
&gt;&gt; Deceleration in final stages. We're
right on top of the marker.
&gt;&gt; Okay, let's keep this airtight. Idlely,
run the checklist.
&gt;&gt; The booster ring isn't designed for
close orbit. To ensure its integrity,
we're releasing it into a safer orbit
around the planet well outside the
atmosphere.
Once the Cassiopia is in orbit around
Taetti F, we'll wake the science crew
and begin the planetary survey for the
landing team on the Andromeda.
&gt;&gt; Manual detach sequence set.
&gt;&gt; Confirmed. Sequence is primed.
&gt;&gt; On my mark. 5 4 3 2 1. Mark.
...
We should have visual on to 30F now.
&gt;&gt; Let's get her up on screen.
...
If only dad could have seen this.
I know.
...
&gt;&gt; Hey, maybe we should land this thing.
Take a little walk before the Andromeda
gets here.
&gt;&gt; Not this again.
&gt;&gt; Look, I get it. Not enough fuel to land
and get home. I'm just saying it's about
legacy.
&gt;&gt; This isn't about fortune and glory.
We were chosen to clear a path for
history to be made. Think about that. We
train together. We launch together. We
execute the mission together. And we
return together.
It's not about what we do here.
It's about what we learn.
The data we gather for the way for the
next great leap in human progress.
...
Okay, he's good.
&gt;&gt; Best of the best.
...
There are anomalous issues regarding the
sleep crew. I'm going to perform a
search of their quarters.
...
&gt;&gt; Sims, you still in engineering?
&gt;&gt; Still busy down here, commander. We need
another 10 minutes.
&gt;&gt; Suits me just fine.
...
Don't have time to stand around. We need
to get this done before Stafford has my
head.
...
Well, at least they made the wakeup
cake.
...
You used to work with Young's dad,
right?
Bill Young. They don't make him like
that anymore.
&gt;&gt; Is she like him?
&gt;&gt; Are young? I mean,
&gt;&gt; the apple didn't fall far from that
tree. Ever since she could walk, she'd
blow out the candles on her dad's
birthday cake. Make a wish, she'd say,
because mine already came true.
She'd always make the same wish.
I want to be an astronaut just like my
daddy.
&gt;&gt; He must have left a big impression on
you both.
&gt;&gt; He was a legend.
...
What defines humanity?
&gt;&gt; What?
&gt;&gt; Our ability to collaborate
to
...
Wait,
&gt;&gt; I'll have you gardening with me in
hydroponics. Don't you worry.
&gt;&gt; It's important to be mindful.
...
&gt;&gt; We're awake for your journey there while
the main crew sleeps.
...
Hey, Um, we're getting pretty bored out
here, though. Carter and I seem to have
different meanings of bored. While I
work through the coffee blends, Carter
cooks up fun tasks for us to carry out
during downtime.
...
Yesterday, I was on an inventory check.
I found something odd.
Turns out the stasis fluid for the
cruise return trip isn't the same mix
they're using now.
Carter and I trained for this procedure,
but we never used different stasis
fluids.
Why weren't we briefed on this?
...
I'll let you know if I find out more.
I feel better imagining you on the other
side. You with your green tea, me with
my
mint cherry mocker, apparently.
Cheers.
...
Maintenance error in crew lounge one.
Reconfiguration in progress.
Standby.
...
&gt;&gt; Warning. Airlock locking clamps
released.
All personnel, clear fuel junction 4.
...
Open this door now or I will have you
court marshaled.
&gt;&gt; No [__]
&gt;&gt; Sims
...
Hey, I'm reading an air lock at fuel
junction 4. What's going on?
&gt;&gt; Shut the air lock.
&gt;&gt; Isolate, are you in there?
&gt;&gt; Stafford, feel the air lock.
&gt;&gt; Mitch, seal it up right now.
&gt;&gt; Pressurization cycle engaged. I'll go
ahead
in 5 4 3 2 1
...
&gt;&gt; Are you safe? Reporting in.
&gt;&gt; It was It was Sims.
She tried to kill me.
&gt;&gt; What? Why would she do that?
Everyone, I need you to remain.
Damn it.
...
&gt;&gt; Maintenance alert. Blockage detected in
ventilation system.
...
Every part of this mission was
meticulously planned.
Life, however, is unpredictable.
Whatever factors lie within our control,
the universe always has a plan of its
own.
...
How do I know it's you?
&gt;&gt; Don't be ridiculous, Zernin.
...
&gt;&gt; I'm warning you. Stay back.
&gt;&gt; Easier to say from behind a locked door.
...
Sherman,
I've been thinking about that story you
told.
That little boy who always won at hide
and seek, walking calmly up and down the
roads.
Are you calm now, sir?
&gt;&gt; Because this isn't a game anymore.
...
It's dark
where we're going. There is no light.
...
Just come out.
You know how this is going to end.
...
&gt;&gt; It's okay, sir. I can help.
&gt;&gt; Progress can be ugly.
&gt;&gt; At Corinth, our focus has always been
...
Sims,
this is Stafford.
Talk to me.
...
Sims,
&gt;&gt; can someone please tell me what the [__]
is going on here?
&gt;&gt; I've got Carter here and it looks
...
I need your status and location.
Sims,
are you safe? At least tell me that.
...
&gt;&gt; I've checked the cameras. Nothing.
&gt;&gt; They must still be in the guts.
God damn it. Why aren't they answering?
&gt;&gt; Decomposition's already started. They've
been dead for hours.
&gt;&gt; Must have been there since we woke.
Doesn't make any [__] sense, man.
Stafford spoke to them. We heard them.
&gt;&gt; Help me seal the pod.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
...
&gt;&gt; Okay.
Push now.
I am. It's stuck.
&gt;&gt; [__] What? We're going to have to break
it. What? Are you kidding me?
...
Lord have mercy.
So, what do we see?
...
&gt;&gt; Stab wound to the abdominal region.
&gt;&gt; Looks different to the rest of the
wounds. Could be the cause of death.
&gt;&gt; We don't know that.
...
No com in it.
&gt;&gt; It's missing.
&gt;&gt; Interesting.
...
&gt;&gt; Utility strap is missing.
&gt;&gt; Shame they aren't chipped. No way of
tracking it.
...
&gt;&gt; Legs shattered. No indication whether
pre or postmortem.
&gt;&gt; Mitchell, get up to the flight deck. The
burn window is fast approaching and we
can't let anything endanger this
mission. Even something like this.
...
What are we going to do?
&gt;&gt; We need to find Sims.
...
&gt;&gt; We need an autopsy.
&gt;&gt; We should wake Dr. Cooper.
&gt;&gt; We don't have time. We're almost at
orbit.
&gt;&gt; Doesn't make sense.
&gt;&gt; How could I have gotten her so wrong?
&gt;&gt; People change. A lot can happen in 4
years.
...
&gt;&gt; Nobody has spent this long isolated in
space.
&gt;&gt; Space psychosis is a myth. They trained
for this.
...
You were right to be concerned.
I should have listened.
&gt;&gt; My mind is on the mission success.
Pride and ego do not factor.
It's important. You know that.
&gt;&gt; Let's get this pod sealed and file a
report.
...
&gt;&gt; I know there's some major [__] going
down right now, but uh we're real tight
on that mission marker. We got to get
into orbit. Commander,
&gt;&gt; on our way, son.
Eisel Young, you go ahead. I'll be right
behind you.
...
&gt;&gt; I will find you, Sims. And when I do,
you will face the consequences of your
actions.
...
Young, are you at your
Yes, commander.
&gt;&gt; Good. How long have we got?
&gt;&gt; Orbital window closing rapidly,
commander.
&gt;&gt; I have vector control. You're on main
engines.
&gt;&gt; Already on it.
...
&gt;&gt; Buckle up.
&gt;&gt; Orbital window closing in 43 seconds.
&gt;&gt; Young, you got this
&gt;&gt; under control.
...
We've had some knocks, but this is what
we train for. Let's pull together.
Let's do it for Carter.
...
&gt;&gt; Heading looks good. Not reading any
drift.
&gt;&gt; Clean. No, you're too kind.
&gt;&gt; H, strange. I'm picking up some odd
readouts in near orbit. Stellar objects.
&gt;&gt; We'll run a full scan when we're stable.
&gt;&gt; Prepare for breaking burn.
&gt;&gt; Final checks, please. Guidance,
&gt;&gt; go.
&gt;&gt; Orientation,
&gt;&gt; Thrust,
&gt;&gt; go. Let's send it.
&gt;&gt; Command is go.
&gt;&gt; Firing in five, 4, 3, 2, 1. Come on.
...
Vector stable. Approaching orbital
trajectory. Disengage burn in 3 2 1
...
decreasing.
&gt;&gt; Mitchell, give me a minute.
&gt;&gt; Cut the burn.
&gt;&gt; I said a minute. We've lost orbital
velocity. We need to recalibrate right
now or we're hitting that planet.
&gt;&gt; I'm locked out.
&gt;&gt; Is your panel connected?
&gt;&gt; I I don't know. The engine's not
responding.
...
&gt;&gt; He's right. It's mechanical. I can't cut
the engines either.
&gt;&gt; [__] We're out of time.
...
&gt;&gt; Did you cut the engines?
&gt;&gt; No. The fuel tank bombed out. We are 30
seconds from atmosphere.
&gt;&gt; Impact velocity
&gt;&gt; survival, but it depends on atmospheric
drag.
&gt;&gt; Y,
&gt;&gt; bring us round for a landing.
&gt;&gt; Starting error break. I'm going to fly
it in with the RCS.
...
&gt;&gt; RCS reserves to 82%.
&gt;&gt; Get ready to dump it into the retros.
&gt;&gt; Ready.
...
Wait,
the landing computer's offline. We're
going in blind.
&gt;&gt; 40 clicks to impact.
&gt;&gt; I can bring the landing computer online
manually.
&gt;&gt; Staff, stay down. It's too dangerous.
Commander, we need that computer online.
&gt;&gt; You can fix it, but you go now.
We can't risk going in dark. Do it.
&gt;&gt; I'm going in. 20 clicks to impact. Stop
it.
...
&gt;&gt; The backup computer's disabled.
&gt;&gt; We shut it down to repower the ship. Get
back to your seat.
...
50%. You got to bring the nose up. We're
too fast.
&gt;&gt; Seven clicks.
&gt;&gt; [__] I can't see jack. [__] Stand by
for retros. I got it.
Move.
...
Cooper,
&gt;&gt; hold still. I'm almost done.
...
&gt;&gt; What's going on? Where's the rest of the
crew?
&gt;&gt; We're not sure what's going on yet.
Right now, I need you to stay calm so I
can complete the wake up process.
...
&gt;&gt; We got gravity.
&gt;&gt; Where are the sleep technicians?
&gt;&gt; They're
not able to help at the moment. Cod is
dead.
...
What happened to him?
&gt;&gt; We don't know.
&gt;&gt; My god, he's mangled. Poor Carter.
&gt;&gt; We can't get a line through to the
Oracle or the rest of the crew. We don't
know what's going on.
...
&gt;&gt; He's been dead for days.
&gt;&gt; Looks like it. But his pod was only
sealed an hour ago.
&gt;&gt; That doesn't make sense.
&gt;&gt; No, it certainly doesn't.
Warning, critical systems failure.
...
&gt;&gt; We've taken some major damage.
Lower decks in particular.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, we know. What we don't know is why
we have gravity. Either we've crash
landed or the ship's entered a
catastrophic spin. Right now, there's no
way of telling. Breach seals have locked
us in here.
&gt;&gt; Stafford, do you read?
...
&gt;&gt; Okay, Williams. You really want to wake
the boss up to this nightmare?
&gt;&gt; It's not safe to leave him under in an
emergency. I'll wake him.
[__] His blood stabilizer is not
responding. We need to get him through.
Wake up immediately.
Release the emergency lock on the back
next to the hinge. Left left side. Got
it.
I'm going to give him a quick pulse to
wake him. Get ready to
[__]
Cernin, hold him down.
...
He's hemorrhaging.
&gt;&gt; He's fine. His body's just reacting to
the heavy dose.
&gt;&gt; Well, that's some reaction.
&gt;&gt; Better a nose bleed now than an aneurysm
later.
...
&gt;&gt; We need to override those breed seals.
We could get through with some wedge
tools. Right.
&gt;&gt; Right. Tool stores behind that bulkhead
over there,
&gt;&gt; though. There should be the maintenance
tunnel.
Come with me. If we break that breach
seal, we can regroup with the crew and
find out what happened here.
&gt;&gt; Assuming they're still alive. Well, I
hope you've got your pilot's license
because if you're right, you're flying
us home.
Monitor him closely and holler if you
need me. It'll be 2 minutes.
...
&gt;&gt; You okay back there, Anders?
&gt;&gt; Fine. Just get us out of here.
...
&gt;&gt; It's cold in here. You just woke up.
Keep moving. You'll warm up.
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Doc.
...
&gt;&gt; You think Williams is going to pull
through?
&gt;&gt; Yeah,
&gt;&gt; you'll be fine.
&gt;&gt; Not afraid of tight spaces, are you,
Cooper?
&gt;&gt; Please. I was a marine. We to crawl
through [__] for fun.
&gt;&gt; Did you see that?
All I can see is your act. Cernin,
&gt;&gt; I thought I saw movement.
&gt;&gt; It's dark. Just keep focused.
...
down here to the right.
&gt;&gt; Do you even know where you're going?
&gt;&gt; We need to go up, I think.
...
There's the tool store.
&gt;&gt; Door's unpowered.
&gt;&gt; So, what can we do?
&gt;&gt; Uh, repower it, I guess.
Look at this place.
&gt;&gt; You sound like a kid in a candy store.
&gt;&gt; Let's grab the wedge tools, get back to
the pot room.
...
&gt;&gt; Hey, Mom. Just had dinner. I know space
food has come a long way, but no amount
of salt can make clones meat powder
compared to your cooking.
I'd kill for some manser dah right now.
...
We're pretty close to Satus, so I
thought I'd check in on the Andromeda
sleep crew.
I've spent almost 2 hours waiting on a
reply. I thought they'd be excited to
hear from someone else, but they're
obviously far too busy.
...
&gt;&gt; Great to hear your voice, Cassopia.
How you doing out there? Breaking
records. So, neat idea, but we'll have
to pass on that remote chess game. Earth
wants us to keep this frequency clear.
Okay, you'll also win. Got to admit that
factors into our decision, too. Anyhow,
be good, be patient, be kind to each
other. Still a ways to go.
Sans.
&gt;&gt; Sorry, Mom. J calls.
...
It reminds me of my husband, Mikail.
&gt;&gt; He passed, didn't he?
&gt;&gt; A while ago now, but we made a promise
to each other before he died. He
promised he'd find me again in the next
life.
&gt;&gt; And what did you promise him?
&gt;&gt; I promised to honor him by living a life
that he can be proud of.
He's watching over you, I bet.
...
Mikail was so sure he was going to be
reborn,
so excited to know what lay beyond.
He was at peace at the end.
I take a lot of comfort from that.
Frankly, Cernin, I could use some of his
optimism.
&gt;&gt; I'll tell him when I see him again.
&gt;&gt; Come on. We better get back to the
others.
...
&gt;&gt; You know how to use that?
&gt;&gt; I know how to bonk you on the head if
you keep asking dumb questions.
...
Boom.
Let's get out of here.
&gt;&gt; Your vitals are stable, but you
experienced a minor seizure during the
wakeup procedure.
&gt;&gt; Miss me?
...
We're lucky to have you here. You know,
you're the second smartest person I
know.
&gt;&gt; Second smartest after you. Oh, I meant
Eley. Okay. You're the third smartest
person I know.
&gt;&gt; Why are you being so nice to me? Am I
dying?
How long do I have, Doc?
&gt;&gt; No, you're good. I'll take care of you.
I'll be back in a minute. Just got to
get that door open.
...
Here is Cooper now. Told you she
wouldn't be long.
&gt;&gt; Mr. Williams, how are you feeling?
&gt;&gt; Uh, I'm okay.
What's going on here?
What's happened?
...
&gt;&gt; There's no need to worry, Mr. Williams.
You just need to remain calm and
relaxed. Once your condition has
stabilized, we can give you a full
report on what we know.
&gt;&gt; I do feel pretty woozy.
&gt;&gt; That's okay. Just remain seated. Take
some deep breaths. It takes a while to
settle down, but it will. Promise.
Anders, stay with Williams. We need to
get this door open right away. Doc,
...
Eley.
Is everyone through wake up?
&gt;&gt; We had a problem with Williams, but he
seems to be
stable.
&gt;&gt; There's something we need to know.
...
&gt;&gt; What's going on?
I'll keep this brief.
The flight crew was woken by a minor
meteorite impact. It penetrated multiple
decks and unsurprisingly caused some
system failures.
&gt;&gt; That's it.
&gt;&gt; No, we had a series of operational
challenges getting into orbit. And
&gt;&gt; you said this would be brief.
&gt;&gt; We had to land on TaoF.
&gt;&gt; What? This mission was not configured
for a landing. What does that mean?
&gt;&gt; We don't have enough fuel to get home.
&gt;&gt; What?
That sounds like a bit of an oversight.
Who made that decision?
&gt;&gt; Me. And it wasn't an oversight.
&gt;&gt; We weren't given enough fuel to land and
take off again. It's to stop us stealing
the Andromeda's limelight. Did you not
even skim read the mission brief?
&gt;&gt; I think we deserve a little more trust.
&gt;&gt; It's not about trust.
It's about controlling the parameters of
the mission.
&gt;&gt; If you say so.
&gt;&gt; And for now, no way to contact anyone
for help. Our longrange transmitter was
damaged in the crash, and we need to run
repairs.
Until then, we can only receive messages
from Earth. We can't talk back.
&gt;&gt; Is that how Carter died in the crash?
&gt;&gt; No.
Then what happened to him?
&gt;&gt; We don't have all the facts yet.
&gt;&gt; What do you mean?
...
&gt;&gt; During our hibernation, it looks like
Sims suffered a psychotic episode.
She killed Carter.
She may have even contributed to the
crash.
...
&gt;&gt; Commander Stafford,
&gt;&gt; stop.
Do you mean to tell me that I've
invested billions of dollars, several
years of my life and traveled halfway
across the galaxy on a mission that has
fallen apart before it's even got
started? This is what I wake up to.
...
And to top it off, a murder.
Are you [__] kidding me?
I had your fullest assurance that these
two were vetted painstakingly out of
thousands of potential cand
...
before jumping to conclusions.
&gt;&gt; You'd better get those answers fast
because I am seriously starting to doubt
your competence.
...
Mr. Williams,
&gt;&gt; I'm fine. It's just
&gt;&gt; my head hurts like hell.
&gt;&gt; I'm giving you an antiepileptic. It'll
ease the pain and relieve the pressure
on your blood system.
&gt;&gt; Please tell me Sims isn't still out
there.
&gt;&gt; I'm afraid she is. We believe she's
using the maintenance layers to evade
surveillance.
...
Sir, I'd like to suggest we conduct a
reconnaissance of the ship to locate
her. It's not safe to tackle any other
issues until this matter is resolved.
&gt;&gt; Who put you in charge?
&gt;&gt; With respect, Mr. Williams, you did.
&gt;&gt; I want to speak with Stafford now.
...
This This is [__] man.
Stafford,
...
it's game over. I know it. It's over.
Say your [__] prayers cuz we're not
getting out of this one.
What the [__] are we going to do, man?
What are we going to do? Hey, please
shut up.
&gt;&gt; You're not listening.
Can't you see what's happening here?
&gt;&gt; I said shut up.
&gt;&gt; What the [__] is your problem?
...
&gt;&gt; You're meant to squeeze it.
If we're going to mitigate this mess, if
we're going to survive, then I need you
to get me a damage assessment.
&gt;&gt; How are the others?
&gt;&gt; As well as can be expected.
&gt;&gt; I would never put us in danger.
Especially
not Stafford.
&gt;&gt; It was more likely a technical or a
mechanical fault.
&gt;&gt; Exactly.
&gt;&gt; Come on. We got a mission to salvage. We
need that damage report and we need to
find Sims.
&gt;&gt; We can't leave him here.
&gt;&gt; You're right. Get him to a spot.
...
He didn't get to complete his last
mission.
&gt;&gt; I know.
&gt;&gt; He looked after us for so long.
Feels kind of right that we look after
him now.
&gt;&gt; After my dad passed away,
Stafford had always kept this
consistency in my life.
&gt;&gt; Back then, I needed that so much.
...
I never pictured having to do this
without him.
&gt;&gt; My dad set the bar pretty low, but
Stafford passed it and then some. Things
always felt up and down between us, but
he always saw the best in me. I was the
[__] greatest.
...
&gt;&gt; Do you read?
&gt;&gt; Continue your sweep. We'll be in bridge
ops running damage diagnostics.
...
&gt;&gt; [__] I can't even bring myself to do
this.
&gt;&gt; We need to
...
Eley, this is Cooper. We're on the crew
deck.
&gt;&gt; Head for the technician's quarter. Sims
was down there, and I want to know why.
Be careful. She could be anywhere.
&gt;&gt; So, no eyes on her.
&gt;&gt; No, the monitoring systems are still
damaged. We're working on them now. Good
luck.
...
&gt;&gt; Beautiful. Feels like we're going to
need more than luck.
Okay, let's split up.
&gt;&gt; What?
&gt;&gt; If we do this in pairs, we'll cover more
ground. Once we've done a sweep, we'll
converge on their quarters.
&gt;&gt; And if we find them,
&gt;&gt; you keep safe and you ported over comms.
Cernin, you take Mr. Williams. Anders,
you're with me.
&gt;&gt; Hey, take care, Cooper.
&gt;&gt; You, too.
...
God, it's been trashed. We need to get
to the other side of the wreckage.
...
&gt;&gt; What do you think happened to her?
&gt;&gt; I don't know, but I know Sims is no
killer.
&gt;&gt; You've got to admit it doesn't look
good.
&gt;&gt; She wouldn't hurt a fly.
&gt;&gt; Humanity's been given her better than I
do. Could be a stowway.
&gt;&gt; Someone snuck on board before you left
&gt;&gt; and lived undetected for 4 years.
&gt;&gt; What's your explanation? Aliens.
&gt;&gt; All right, let's just find them.
...
A power cell could be handy given all
the outages.
...
&gt;&gt; Wow.
6 months.
Has it really been that long?
I've never known something to go by
quickly.
&gt;&gt; Grab the power cell from the door.
&gt;&gt; I miss you.
&gt;&gt; I'm seeing a lot of hiding places.
&gt;&gt; We miss you.
&gt;&gt; We stick together, we'll be fine.
&gt;&gt; Daddy,
...
doesn't like
&gt;&gt; Let's get out of here.
I've been explaining how important your
mission is and how proud of you we both
are and how big she's going to be when
you come home.
&gt;&gt; Come home, Daddy.
...
&gt;&gt; Huh?
&gt;&gt; What?
...
&gt;&gt; How you holding up?
I'm stuck on an alien planet with a
bunch of people I barely know.
If I hadn't taken that transfer, I'd be
safe at home right now.
...
They're stuck with you, Anders. Think
how they must feel. Hey, I'm delightful
once you break through the quirks, which
takes time and patience.
Yeah, I guess you can be. I can feel
that sunny disposition running out
pretty soon though. Then you'll be in
trouble. Company made a big mistake
sending me here.
...
&gt;&gt; You know what being in the Marines
taught me? Sometimes you've just got to
get down on all fours and take one.
&gt;&gt; Give it the old college try.
&gt;&gt; Precisely what I was going to say.
Ra baby.
...
Wow.
6 months.
Has it really been that long?
I've never known something to go by so
quickly and so slowly all at once.
...
&gt;&gt; You hear that? The voice is in your head
again. No, listen.
Sounds like a messenger ping.
&gt;&gt; Oh [__] Yeah.
Has to be nearby.
...
&gt;&gt; Has it really been that long?
I've never known something to go by so
quickly and so slowly all at once.
...
&gt;&gt; Sorry it's taking so long to message.
Hope you haven't missed me too much.
I I've been trying to scrape a report
from Kurdis in preparation for orbit,
but everything it sent us so far is
classified.
Don't tell Carter,
but I may have borrowed William's
utility strap. I figured he might have
access. I was [__] right. And it's
not just Kipus. He's got a private line
with the Oracle. I tried to dig into it,
but his utility strap has extra security
protections.
Something's up. And Williams is in on
it. Meanwhile, we are supposed to sit
here in the dark.
I better put this back before Carter
notices.
...
This is Thomas Carter, 48 hours from
flight crew. Wake up. Something's wrong
with Sims. I I don't know. She She
attacked me. I Oh, God. She's trying to
kill me.
We were repairing an impact to the hull.
We separated to repair different areas
of the ship, but then
that's not supposed to happen. She was
psychologically screamed.
...
&gt;&gt; Eley, we found Carter's Ustrap. You need
to see this.
Understood. Let's review when you're
back. Be careful.
&gt;&gt; We'd better meet up with the other two.
Yeah, you're right.
...
Eley, we're in crew quarters.
No sign of her yet.
&gt;&gt; Keep looking
&gt;&gt; this way.
...
Jesus.
[__]
What the hell was that?
&gt;&gt; Jeez.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, you almost took my
&gt;&gt; You cannot go in there. It goes against
every scientific protocol I know.
&gt;&gt; That was alien, right?
&gt;&gt; Open it back up. At the very least, we
need to grab a sample.
&gt;&gt; I saw enough. It's definitely organic,
possibly hazardous, maybe even
infectious. OP section 4, paragraph 13.
Any potential extraterrestrial
substance.
&gt;&gt; That's not your decision to make. This
is a once- ina-lifetime opportunity. And
this is my ship
&gt;&gt; and I'm the science officer on this
ship. We can't risk it spreading. We
need to lock this area down and take the
time to set up proper safety. We
&gt;&gt; don't have time. Just grab a mask and
get in there.
...
&gt;&gt; Anders is right. We can't risk
contamination.
&gt;&gt; Cernin, back me up.
Sorry, but I agree with Williams. We
need to know what we're dealing with,
and the more time we have to analyze it,
the better.
&gt;&gt; Precisely.
&gt;&gt; You really think this is a good idea?
&gt;&gt; Yes, I do. I'm the one who pays the
checks. I'm the one who breaks the tie.
We're taking a sample.
&gt;&gt; I'll take it. I'm fine, Anders.
Hand it over. I got this.
...
&gt;&gt; I voiced my concerns and I want that on
record.
...
We should get this straight to the lab.
&gt;&gt; Wait, I'm coming with you. It's not safe
to be alone.
...
We talk about taking to the stars as if
we're the only ones among them. The
universe doesn't share our hubris.
It doesn't care about our odds.
...
at least we're not running on empty yet.
&gt;&gt; Oxygen levels dropping. Oxygen recovery
and stabilization required.
&gt;&gt; Great. I'll add that to my list along
with getting to the scanner and trying
not to die.
...
&gt;&gt; Our focus has always been the same.
&gt;&gt; Kick that can further down the road.
Move forwards. We have to look at where
we are. Sometimes the reality is ugly.
&gt;&gt; Check it out.
&gt;&gt; Not everyone.
&gt;&gt; This camera feed with his whole area.
&gt;&gt; One of us could guide the other three.
&gt;&gt; We're only straws.
&gt;&gt; I'll go.
&gt;&gt; Corinth,
&gt;&gt; you guide me.
&gt;&gt; Humanity
first.
&gt;&gt; You sure?
...
Okay, now take the door ahead on your
right.
...
&gt;&gt; All right, now get into the vent. Is
that you, Albert?
...
&gt;&gt; Warning. Unidentified group.
&gt;&gt; Stop him. Wait there until he's passed.
I'll say when.
...
&gt;&gt; quick, hide behind that desk you just
passed.
...
You should have given up. Now I have to
learn.
&gt;&gt; Now into the kitchen, then take the
guards out. Close the door.
...
&gt;&gt; Hold there. Stay in the office till
they're distracted.
...
&gt;&gt; It's not too late to change your mind.
I'll make it quick.
...
&gt;&gt; Okay. You need to unlock that door so I
can get over to you.
...
Go
through that door.
...
Hey, teamwork makes the dream work. Shut
up.
...
Our mission has suffered a tragedy.
As Stafford's second, it is down to me
to assume command and salvage what I can
of our mission.
...
&gt;&gt; That's it. That's all we're saying.
&gt;&gt; What do you mean?
&gt;&gt; We should perhaps say a few words for
the dead.
...
&gt;&gt; Of course. We remember their service and
their friendship.
May they rest in peace.
&gt;&gt; Stafford and Carter,
&gt;&gt; rest their souls.
&gt;&gt; We have crashlanded in the Bernell
quadrant of Taedi.
&gt;&gt; Damage is
significant.
Worsened by the mountain we clipped on
the way down.
&gt;&gt; Yeah,
my bad.
&gt;&gt; I'm assuming we're grounded.
&gt;&gt; Correct. Even if we had enough fuel,
there's no way we're getting back in the
air.
Our only option now is to hold out until
the Andromeda arrives.
&gt;&gt; How much air do we have?
&gt;&gt; Life support can keep us breathing, but
the crash has damaged our FTL antenna.
We have no way to contact the Andromeda
or Earth.
&gt;&gt; Can we repair it?
&gt;&gt; Yes, but it'll take time.
&gt;&gt; The ship is in a bad state.
&gt;&gt; Security alert.
...
unidentifiable organic matter on
science.
&gt;&gt; So, are we going to talk about the
growth?
&gt;&gt; I want to do more than talk about it. I
want to rinse that sample for everything
it can tell us.
&gt;&gt; As far as I'm concerned, this is an
entirely undocumented extraterrestrial
life form. Given the extent it's grown,
it must have come on board with that
meteorite.
I mean, it's obvious, right? Meteorite
hits, growth appears, Sims goes mad.
Doesn't take a genius to connect the
dots.
...
&gt;&gt; You could be right. If it's any
consolation, I hope to God I'm not.
&gt;&gt; We've got a gun on this ship, right?
If she's out there whacking people, we
should arm ourselves.
...
This is the only weapon on this ship
issued to Stafford for exactly this
eventuality.
Under code 552 of the Corinth captain's
charter, I authorized the use of this
weapon for the protection of the crew
and the mission.
The Oracle can't locate her. Seems like
she's gone to ground in the maintenance
layers.
&gt;&gt; If she's in the maintenance layers, it
won't be easy to find her. It's a maze
down there.
&gt;&gt; It's a maze, but one I designed.
...
If we welt shut the breach seals here,
here, and here, we can be sure they're
locked into this sector. Then it's just
a case of sweeping the tunnels and
locking down the bulkhead sequentially.
forcing them into a corner here.
&gt;&gt; So, how do we get in there?
&gt;&gt; There's a secondary access tunnel. We
can use it to get into the reactor
funnel without being detected.
&gt;&gt; So, we need to close the seals on all
those maintenance tunnels.
Will that hold her?
&gt;&gt; Yes. And any use of her wet stool will
not only slow her down, it will also
flag her on the system. One of us needs
to get in there to track and detain her.
&gt;&gt; I'll do it.
&gt;&gt; Okay. Dr. Cooper can go with you.
&gt;&gt; Very well. Find Sims, repair the
antenna, reestablish contact with the
Andromeda.
&gt;&gt; If we're lucky, we'll all make it home,
too.
&gt;&gt; How shall I proceed with the substance?
&gt;&gt; Find out what it is and where it came
from. Everyone, get prepped. rendevu in
30 minutes.
...
&gt;&gt; We can salvage the mission. We just need
to trust each other just like Stafford
trusted us.
&gt;&gt; You have our full support, Commander.
...
Okay, I set up the private channel. Go
ahead and switch frequencies.
&gt;&gt; Switching now.
&gt;&gt; You hear me?
&gt;&gt; Nice and clean.
...
You doing all right?
&gt;&gt; Just feels much harder without Stafford.
&gt;&gt; I know.
&gt;&gt; Nicely. We've reached subsection D5.
&gt;&gt; If you locate the maintenance terminal,
you should be able to override the
shutters.
...
&gt;&gt; Okay.
Should be through here. Got it.
...
You don't want to discharge that in
here.
&gt;&gt; I know how to handle a gun. Car gave you
weapons training.
&gt;&gt; The basics, but I used to hang out at
the range a lot.
Ready?
&gt;&gt; Nope.
Somebody's got to do it.
&gt;&gt; Follow the white rabbit.
...
Cooper will seal the bulkheads behind
you as you move.
&gt;&gt; Whoever's down there will be forced into
a dead end.
...
I see. We're at junction 13.
&gt;&gt; Okay. You all good down there?
&gt;&gt; Yep, we're good.
...
What are we going to do when we find
her?
&gt;&gt; That depends.
&gt;&gt; On what?
&gt;&gt; If she cooperates.
...
First shutter.
&gt;&gt; Opening the first shutter.
...
&gt;&gt; Subsection 4 clear.
Sealing the bulkhead.
...
I'm at shutter 2.
&gt;&gt; Opening shutter 2.
...
Lhata
opening shutter 3.
...
Don't don't [__]
young. Young, what's going on?
...
But Sims,
she's dead.
&gt;&gt; What? Are you serious?
&gt;&gt; She's dead.
She's been dead for ages.
&gt;&gt; That's impossible.
&gt;&gt; I'm serious. Whoever we're searching
for, it's not Sims.
&gt;&gt; If it's not her, then we don't know what
we're up against. Get back here.
&gt;&gt; Young Cooper, are you two okay?
Whatever's down there is trapped. I'm
moving on.
&gt;&gt; Tongue, don't do it. Young, come back.
...
&gt;&gt; Whoever it is, they're moving around to
the reactor array. We've got them
cornered.
...
You've got to be [__] me. How the
[__] did they get away?
&gt;&gt; Not many places left down here for them
to hide.
&gt;&gt; The whole area is locked down. Only way
out was through that vent. Only place
they could be is
...
&gt;&gt; Eley. Can you see us on camera?
&gt;&gt; I can see movement in there.
...
Yum. You all right?
I'm coming down.
...
Young, you there? If you can hear me,
you need to extend the bridge. I'll look
for another way around.
...
Warning. System error identified. Manual
override required.
Step away.
...
Eley, whoever it is, they're toast. They
fell into the reactor funnel.
...
When things get ugly, it all comes down
to survival of the fittest.
But when you're stripped down to your
bones,
can you bear to see what you're really
made of?
...
Engage waste burn.
&gt;&gt; Waste burn activated.
...
&gt;&gt; Should have been me going down there.
&gt;&gt; She's safe.
It's what she found we should be worried
about.
&gt;&gt; These are the images Cooper captured.
It's the meteorite
lodged in the reactor.
&gt;&gt; Are you sure whoever attacked you is
dead?
&gt;&gt; Positive.
&gt;&gt; They fell into the reactor array.
&gt;&gt; This was Sims, right?
&gt;&gt; I told you there's someone else down
there.
&gt;&gt; How many [__] murderers can there be
on one ship?
&gt;&gt; There could have been a blind spot in
the ship's design that allowed a
storeway to get in and hide.
As you know, I couldn't get the security
arrangements I wanted for pre-launch.
&gt;&gt; So, you're saying that the oceans of
money I threw at you still weren't
enough to solve your security problems?
I'd have thought that, money aside, the
crew would notice. An extra person on
board.
...
&gt;&gt; Sir, it's dealt with. Whoever it was,
they're dead.
That meteorite is organic.
A living substance.
It must have spread through the vents to
Carter and Sims quarters.
&gt;&gt; A living substance.
Fascinating.
&gt;&gt; So, how much do we know about the
substance?
&gt;&gt; Well, as I mentioned, it's organic
and it's extraterrestrial, rapidly
replicating,
almost certainly toxic.
I've quarantined the deck and sealed the
air vents. There is no way that thing is
spreading further.
&gt;&gt; So, it's locked up until the Andromeda
arrives.
&gt;&gt; Gives us time to figure out how to
safely transport a sample home.
&gt;&gt; Are you for real?
&gt;&gt; It's a breathtaking discovery. We can't
just leave it.
&gt;&gt; We have no idea what it is. For all we
know, it could wipe out the entire human
race with a single
&gt;&gt; Earth can provide the directives. It's
my company, my directives.
&gt;&gt; Sorry to interject, but we are still cut
off from Earth.
&gt;&gt; Now that Sims is dealt with, I should
think about carrying out repairs to the
transmitter.
&gt;&gt; Go ahead, Mitchell. Continue the damage
assessment from up here. Anders, you
need to analyze that sample.
&gt;&gt; I'll help.
Let's get that transmitter up and
running. Earth needs to know what's
happening here. Move out.
...
&gt;&gt; The transmitter isn't responding at all.
I need to reroute the power and repair
the array using our drones.
&gt;&gt; Can I get an ETA on that?
&gt;&gt; Should be done in just under an hour,
but then it's down to engineering. I'll
have power ruted in 3 to 4 hours. Mr.
Williams and Young are helping out, too.
No rest for the wicked.
&gt;&gt; Good. Keep me updated.
&gt;&gt; Guess we're doing this by ourselves,
then.
&gt;&gt; Great.
...
Anders.
&gt;&gt; Well, Mr. Williams,
you still want a little pet to take
home?
&gt;&gt; In circumstances like these,
everything should be on the table.
&gt;&gt; Eley, get up here. There's something you
need to see.
&gt;&gt; Understood.
...
Unbelievable.
I've never seen anything like this
before.
&gt;&gt; Did you run a protein analysis?
&gt;&gt; The scanner can't identify it. It's
organic, but unlike any organism we've
ever seen.
Its cellular structure is changing
almost constantly.
It's highly efficient, appearing to
absorb matter in its immediate proximity
and duplicate it.
It's copying whatever it touches.
&gt;&gt; To what end?
&gt;&gt; I don't know. But it's growing. Left
unchecked, it could overwhelm the whole
ship in a matter of days. Oh, cool. Love
that for us.
&gt;&gt; Cooper, give me a hand when you have a
minute. Sure thing.
...
So, what's up?
Could you grab me a sedative from the
chem cabinet? A sedative? Why? I've got
a little experiment I want to conduct.
Just grab the drugs and I'll explain
later. I've heard that one before.
Just do it.
...
Something like Alprazelam or Dazabam.
Creepy, isn't it?
&gt;&gt; I think it's beautiful.
...
You don't remember the incident during
wakeup
doctor supposed to be more forthcoming
with information?
&gt;&gt; Well,
the injection we gave you. Memory loss
can be a side effect.
&gt;&gt; I hate to think I made the wrong call
bringing you on this mission.
There's no room for error.
I'd have thought you'd known that given
what happened on Jessup's station.
...
&gt;&gt; I'm perfectly capable for this job, Mr.
Williams. Jessup station is behind me.
I'm over it. And you have no right
bringing it up.
&gt;&gt; You should focus on the task at hand.
&gt;&gt; Yes, sir.
...
She'd better have a good reason for
this.
...
I got it. You got it.
All right, Coop.
Follow me.
...
Do you think Williams knows more about
this substance than he's letting on?
&gt;&gt; What are you talking about?
&gt;&gt; Like commercial exploitation?
What if this whole mission is an
experiment to expose us to whatever this
thing is?
&gt;&gt; So, you're a conspiracy theorist? You
[__] serious?
&gt;&gt; Deadly serious. No one else reacted that
way when they saw the sample. Do you
really trust him?
...
Why would he crash and burn the ship? He
sunk billions into a ship he's on. It
doesn't make sense. If this is an
experiment, he'd want to bring the
results back to Earth, right? Which
would require a functioning ship.
&gt;&gt; I'm not talking about the crash. Please
clue me into what you're talking about.
He's not stupid. If anyone can see the
dollar signs in this, it's Williams.
He's up to something, Cooper. I I know
it. Look, I'm new to this crew, but
Williams trusts you. If he knows
anything, if he's putting our lives at
risk, we need to do something about it.
What do you know that I don't?
&gt;&gt; I may have kind of accidentally
on purpose had a sneaky peek into his
drop drive. That's impossible. His drive
is security locked and he Oh, you
didn't. Wouldn't be much of a science
officer if I didn't know a few cheeky
little command overrides.
...
Anders, you sly old fox. Never change.
&gt;&gt; Why would I? I'm already perfect.
...
&gt;&gt; Williams has his own file stack inside
the Oracle, heavily encrypted.
He's been updating it since he woke up,
talking to her through a line that's
hidden from everyone, including Stafford
and Eley. I mean, he's the boss. He can
do whatever the [__] he likes. [__] him.
It's completely against protocol. Only
command can access the Oracle like that.
He's hiding something. I know it. And
he's putting us all in danger.
...
Then tell Eley. If Williams has broken
protocol, let her deal with it.
&gt;&gt; No way. That means admitting I broke
into his drive.
&gt;&gt; So the pot is calling the kettle black,
is she?
&gt;&gt; This is different. He's hiding something
from the commander. [__] Anders,
why are you like this? Oh, please. You
wouldn't have me any other way. I need
to have a deeper look at that drive, but
it'll take time. I can't have William
sauntering into his office when I am up
to my nuts in his dirty laundry.
&gt;&gt; Oh, no. No. I don't like where this is
heading. Remember that time in Fort
Wayne when those frat boy knuckle
walkers wouldn't take the hint?
&gt;&gt; That was a lifetime ago and that was a
couple of laxatives in a keg. This is a
whole different ball game. Come on,
Coupe. We're not those people anymore.
&gt;&gt; Exactly. You're a whole ass doctor now.
Just hit him with something to send him
to sleep for a few hours. If he twigs,
just say it was a side effect of the
shot we gave him earlier.
[__] it. Okay, I'll do it. I'll send him
to sleep to shut you up if nothing else.
&gt;&gt; Cooper, I [__] love you.
&gt;&gt; Unfortunately, I love you, too.
...
Are we good to go?
Yes. Take a look at our little bundle of
joy
...
here. I'm going to run a small charge
through one of the samples. Watch the
other one.
...
It reacts to the charge wherever I place
it. One sample affects the other at
exactly the same time.
...
It seems to stun it briefly, but it
won't kill it.
&gt;&gt; So, the cells are endangled somehow.
&gt;&gt; Yes. This proves the whole thing is
connected.
One organism.
The growth of almost every organism is
stunted by cold.
If we could freeze the substance,
maybe we could stop it expanding.
&gt;&gt; You know, we've got plenty of oxygen in
the fuel oxidizer tanks.
&gt;&gt; Could we channel liquid oxygen from the
fuel cells into the spectrometer?
&gt;&gt; Well, potentially
not without risks.
Cernin, we've got a job for you. Cernin,
are you reading me?
Damn, this interference.
&gt;&gt; He's still running his damage
assessment. Eisley, can I help?
&gt;&gt; Get to fuel junction 4. We're going to
try something.
...
Are there any further instructions?
&gt;&gt; Until communication is restored, there
are no further directives. Please file
your personnel reports for this cycle
and continue monitoring.
Very well. Prepare the compound for
planetary launch.
&gt;&gt; Of course, Mr. Williams,
...
&gt;&gt; Anders,
I was hoping for some privacy.
&gt;&gt; Sorry, Mr. Williams. I just thought,
well, you wouldn't be the boss unless
you had someone to bring you coffee,
right?
...
Where's yours? Oh,
&gt;&gt; I already had some.
...
&gt;&gt; We are in position to monitor the
experiment. Anders, are you ready?
standing by.
&gt;&gt; Get Williams. He'll want to see this.
...
&gt;&gt; Okay, we've primed the liquid O2 to be
pumped into medical. Just needs Mitchell
to start the pumping process.
...
&gt;&gt; Okay, you little freak. Let's see how
you like this.
&gt;&gt; Take it slow. If we blow the line, we
could trigger an explosion.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, thanks for that, Eley.
...
&gt;&gt; I think it's working. The growth is
decaying.
...
&gt;&gt; Coming up to 12%. Shall I push it
higher?
...
[__]
&gt;&gt; Anders, I'm getting an alarm reading
here. Anders.
Anders, answer me.
...
Anders, what happened?
&gt;&gt; I'm locked in here. The spectromedus
ruptured it. It's leaking liquid oxygen.
&gt;&gt; Get me out. It's [__] burning in
here.
&gt;&gt; Get me out or I'm going to [__]
freeze.
&gt;&gt; Young, the fuel line has caught fire in
the junction room. Mitchell is trapped.
...
I've got her on camera. It looks like
the door has been compromised. Young,
you have to get her out of there.
&gt;&gt; I'm on my way.
...
Williams.
&gt;&gt; What the hell is Williams doing down
there? It
&gt;&gt; doesn't make sense.
&gt;&gt; Mr. Williams, what are you doing? Get
out of there. Let Young deal with this.
&gt;&gt; [__] it. I'm going down.
...
Young, you have to make a choice.
&gt;&gt; Open the goddamn door. Hurry. Can't
stop. Get me out of here.
[__] He's going to get out. It's time.
...
It's Williams. He's still down there.
William, what are you doing? Get out of
there, man. What's he doing?
...
backup fire control systems engaging.
&gt;&gt; Thank God.
...
&gt;&gt; It's okay.
That's it.
feel safe now.
...
&gt;&gt; Are you okay? I'm freezing. Is she
secured? Yeah, I've got her.
...
Please
help. Backup fire control systems
engaging.
...
Oh. Oh my god.
I have never been so happy to be rained
on.
...
Can you still carry out repairs on the
antenna?
&gt;&gt; Well, the tachionic field is charged,
but I can't achieve signal velocity.
&gt;&gt; So, we can receive, but not broadcast.
&gt;&gt; Correct.
&gt;&gt; I'll check if the Oracle can speed up
repairs.
&gt;&gt; Oh, don't worry about me. Just keep me
informed.
...
uncredented investments in the
advancement of space travel and
terraforming technology. The Cassiopia
will be the first man exoplanetary
survey mission with our ultimate goal
being colony transfer.
...
&gt;&gt; Did he really lock me in there?
&gt;&gt; I don't know, but he was the only one
down there.
...
What the [__] did we give him? His
office was trashed. We were meant to
knock him out, not drive him crazy. I do
not like how much we you're putting in
that sentence. This whole thing was your
idea. I copied his drop drive. It'll
take me a while to decrypt the files,
but when I do, we'll know what he was up
to.
&gt;&gt; God damn it. You'd better be right.
As for the growth, it seems to be
quarantined at least. I hope it is. I'm
headed over to Bridge Ops. Are you
there?
&gt;&gt; You must be tired.
&gt;&gt; Can't sleep when there's work to do.
&gt;&gt; Same. Nice to know I'm not.
&gt;&gt; You're still with me, Eley. I think I
lost you. Eley,
&gt;&gt; what?
...
What the [__]
Cooper?
...
What's happening?
What have you done to me,
...
&gt;&gt; Mr. Williams?
How did you get here?
&gt;&gt; What are you talking about?
&gt;&gt; What's the last thing you remember?
&gt;&gt; I
I don't know.
&gt;&gt; We saw you die.
&gt;&gt; Is this real?
&gt;&gt; Of course it's real. I'm right in front
of you.
&gt;&gt; How long has he been here?
&gt;&gt; Anders,
&gt;&gt; will someone please tell me what's going
on?
&gt;&gt; I want you to run every biometric on
Williams that you can.
&gt;&gt; What the hell?
Why can't any of you give me a straight
answer?
What the [__] is happening?
...
&gt;&gt; Are we comfortable with him being able
to move around freely?
&gt;&gt; Whoa. What the [__]
...
Detain him in the secure storage area in
geocscience.
&gt;&gt; You can't just lock me away.
&gt;&gt; You need to come with us. Williams,
...
&gt;&gt; just stay here while we run some tests.
&gt;&gt; What exactly do you expect your tests to
show? This is Boss Jan.
&gt;&gt; You've lost your mind. Just let me out
of here.
&gt;&gt; I'm sorry, Williams. This has to be
done.
&gt;&gt; Let me out of here. This is [__]
I get me out of here. That's an order.
&gt;&gt; You're not authorized to give me orders,
Mr. Williams.
&gt;&gt; It's Williams. I thought we were past
that now. And I am not dead. I would
know if I was dead, wouldn't I?
&gt;&gt; How long is this going to take?
&gt;&gt; It's about
...
&gt;&gt; What's going on?
Warning. Damage to hydroponic systems
identified.
...
&gt;&gt; What is it?
&gt;&gt; Something's happening in hydroponics.
&gt;&gt; What do you mean?
&gt;&gt; There are people there.
&gt;&gt; Oh my god.
...
Stop.
&gt;&gt; They've cut the monitoring systems.
&gt;&gt; Oxygen saturation levels compromised.
Oxygen must remain above 70% to avoid
&gt;&gt; and they've shut down the CO2 SC.
...
&gt;&gt; What's going on? Get me out of here now.
&gt;&gt; Be honest. How long do we have left?
&gt;&gt; With all of us awake and the CO2
scrubbers not working, we might not make
it till the end of the day.
...
&gt;&gt; [__]
&gt;&gt; So, let's get them working again.
&gt;&gt; Every minute counts.
&gt;&gt; I'll do it.
...
Take Cernin. If any of the systems are
down, he's our best shot at fixing them.
&gt;&gt; I'm on it.
&gt;&gt; Wait. You'll be more used with this than
I am.
&gt;&gt; Cernin,
it's me and you, babe.
...
&gt;&gt; Are you sure you're up to it?
&gt;&gt; Yes.
...
Taking risks is part of the job. It's
simple math until you have to live with
the consequences.
And there are some consequences that no
amount of calculation can reconcile.
...
Despite the weather, we are already back
on target for launch
And I cannot stress how much the crew is
excited for this to be happening. After
all these years of preparation,
we are in a place that is
...
Look, I know there's a lot to consider,
but it won't be the same mission without
you.
&gt;&gt; There's a lot about this mission that
doesn't seem the same now. I know,
but we need you. Me and the crew.
...
Stefan,
I don't want to let you or the crew
down,
but what they're asking of what they're
asking us to do.
...
I know you made a promise to my dad,
but the way I see it.
You've already fulfilled that.
&gt;&gt; I promised I'd look after you.
That's not something that ends.
&gt;&gt; You've looked after me already
by showing me how to make my own
decisions.
All I'm asking is that you let me do
that. No,
...
&gt;&gt; you want to choose for yourself. I get
that.
This situation were any different, any
less urgent.
Kid, I'd never asked you to make a call
I didn't think was the right one.
You might not like it, but I need you to
trust me.
Being a leader is about knowing when to
trust and when to make that call.
...
One day, young,
you're going to see that for yourself.
...
Warning. Oxygen saturation levels
compromised.
Oxygen must remain above 70% to avoid
adverse reactions and fatalities.
...
&gt;&gt; Cernin, I found a power cell. I just
need to find a way to get it.
&gt;&gt; Okay. Should I come to you?
&gt;&gt; No, stay put. I'll get it.
...
Error. Clamp detachment required.
&gt;&gt; Damn it.
&gt;&gt; Power supply needed to release clamps.
...
I should be able to move the container
into the gap.
&gt;&gt; Complete
...
You made it.
&gt;&gt; I'll be right over.
...
Mankind has a long history of adversity.
Taking that way of life.
...
Holy [__] Christ.
&gt;&gt; This has got to be why the scrubbers are
damaged.
...
&gt;&gt; Anders, this [__] is all over
hydroponics.
&gt;&gt; Has it reached the CO2 scrubbers? more
than likely.
...
&gt;&gt; Who's there?
Identify yourself.
...
Don't trust him.
&gt;&gt; What are you talking about?
&gt;&gt; The growth. It's alive. It It can change
shape. It can turn into any of us.
That's not Williams.
&gt;&gt; The hell are you talking about?
&gt;&gt; It's true. We can't trust him because
it's not him.
&gt;&gt; He has been acting like a [__] Looney
Tune. Williams, say something. Let us
know this isn't true.
&gt;&gt; You're kidding, right? It's me.
...
Wait, we don't know what he is. The test
is almost finished and then we'll know
for sure.
&gt;&gt; Let's see what you're made of, [__]
&gt;&gt; Not yet. It's not my time.
...
&gt;&gt; CEO LaMarcus Williams.
Seditive detected in bloodstream.
Recommend medical treatment.
...
&gt;&gt; Those those things they can they can
change [__]
...
&gt;&gt; Get me out of here now.
&gt;&gt; Release him. My apologies, sir.
...
Now that everyone's calm down from this
madness.
Who the [__] drugged me?
It's a new one. I'll give you that. This
is my ship, my mission. You are my
employees.
...
&gt;&gt; You.
&gt;&gt; Okay, calm down. Yes, it was me. I was
concerned about your loyalty to this
mission.
&gt;&gt; Oh my god.
&gt;&gt; You tried to kill me.
&gt;&gt; No, I sedated you and it might well have
saved your life.
&gt;&gt; You're out of control. She has to be
dealt with.
&gt;&gt; You did what?
&gt;&gt; She clearly had reasons for what she did
or she wouldn't have done it.
&gt;&gt; Thank you.
&gt;&gt; I don't believe this.
&gt;&gt; It's [__]
...
&gt;&gt; It's one of those things.
&gt;&gt; Anders, is there anything we can use to
scan ourselves?
&gt;&gt; Oh, yes. The scanner outside Bridgeops
runs class A biometrics.
&gt;&gt; Great. Let's go.
&gt;&gt; Run.
...
Damn it.
No.
...
&gt;&gt; Oxygen levels dropping. Oxygen recovery
and stabilization required.
&gt;&gt; Great. I'll add that to my list along
with getting to the scanner and trying
not to die.
&gt;&gt; [__]
...
Young, am I glad I found you?
&gt;&gt; How do we know it's really you?
...
&gt;&gt; I don't trust anyone right now. The
scanner is the only way to be sure.
&gt;&gt; Get away from me,
&gt;&gt; Cooper. Thank god. But we thought you
were
&gt;&gt; Get away,
&gt;&gt; Cooper. It's me.
&gt;&gt; For real. Prove it.
&gt;&gt; The biometric scanner outside Bridgeops.
We were heading there now.
&gt;&gt; You're not getting in the elevator.
It's the only way,
&gt;&gt; Cooper.
You better not be lying.
...
&gt;&gt; Threats alive. Seek alternative air
supply immediately.
...
out.
If you're all who you say you are, the
scanner will let you through.
...
&gt;&gt; Walk through the scanner. Ka, it's me
now. Anders Ka
...
Don't you ever point that thing at me
again.
&gt;&gt; This is nuts. You already scanned me.
&gt;&gt; Shut the [__] up.
&gt;&gt; Move.
...
I know who I am.
&gt;&gt; So prove it,
&gt;&gt; Cooper. I was worried you were
What are you?
...
&gt;&gt; Not one goddamn step.
&gt;&gt; Think very carefully, Cooper. Cooper,
please.
It's me.
She's lying.
&gt;&gt; I told you not one godamn step.
...
Both of you get your asses through the
scanner now.
...
If that's what you want.
No. Get away from her.
...
Do you think it's gone
for now?
Maybe it's figured out. It can't get
through the door.
...
[__]
[__] [__] [__] [__] [__] [__]
[__] [__] What are we going to do?
Calm down.
&gt;&gt; Why should I? We're [__] doomed.
Cooper, I get what you've been through,
but all of us are going through it right
now.
...
What the hell was that anyway? Did you
see what happened to Eley? It wasn't
even them, was it? It was It was like a
a a thing. [__]
whatever this thing is, it doesn't
conform to any known science. There is
no way any organism we know could adapt
itself so quickly, let alone copy
another life form with such precision.
&gt;&gt; But I don't understand.
&gt;&gt; Join the club, mate.
&gt;&gt; No, I mean, why? What reason does it
have to copy us? that that goes beyond
biological imperative. That's
well that implies a level of
intelligence greater than I imagined.
&gt;&gt; These mimics,
they're like the organism's defense
mechanism,
like white blood cells or antibodies.
They identify a hostile presence and
duplicate it to get close to their enemy
without being noticed.
Then they kill it.
&gt;&gt; That explains why they crashed the ship.
They want us dead.
&gt;&gt; We're further away from home than any
human has ever been.
This is their home and we're
trespassing.
...
Oh, [__] Okay. Uh, it's the substance,
the growth. It's like we said, it's
adapting its molecular makeup. It's
duplicating us. I need to think
...
I didn't think things could ever be
worse than Jessup Station, but here we
are. Stafford and Enemy dead. Those
things all over the ship. Oxygen running
out. I can't stop thinking about how
it's all gone wrong at every turn.
Like the whole thing was doomed from the
[__] start. We're going to get out of
this, right, Young?
Tell me we're going home.
[__] Just tell me something.
Give me hope, please.
Yeah.
That's what I thought.
...
&gt;&gt; What the hell are we going to do?
There's no way we can leave this area.
&gt;&gt; Do we even have enough food to hold out?
&gt;&gt; Forget food. The Andromeda is 6 months
away.
We don't even have enough air for the
day.
Is there any way we could redirect the
oxygen into just this compartment?
...
&gt;&gt; That's Karibdis. Well, hello beautiful.
How did you find us?
...
&gt;&gt; The Caribus mission was comprised of 20
landing probes, each with their own
drone recon unit and long range FTL
transmitter.
It is pretty incredible. Our planned
orbit was to fly over each probe
individually and collect data. But even
so, the chances of us crash landing
within range of one is frankly,
it's a bit of a miracle.
&gt;&gt; Well, thank God for that. We're in need
of a miracle right now.
&gt;&gt; If we follow this drone back to its
probe, we could use its transmitter to
broadcast an SOS to the Andromeda, and
they could rescue us. Is there any
chance we could hold out here for 6
months? There's got to be a way.
Restrict oxygen to justice compartment.
Foam seal the doors. Close off any
ancillary events.
&gt;&gt; Let's get out there, then.
&gt;&gt; First, we need to agree on what message
we're going to send to the Andromeda.
&gt;&gt; What do you mean?
...
&gt;&gt; Please don't tell me some red tape is
going to stop us getting home.
&gt;&gt; This ship is infected with an alien
organism. For all we know, it could be
in our own bloodstreams by now.
Directive 8020 states, "The Earth must
be protected from extraterrestrial
matter carried by a spacecraft returning
from another planet.
If the Andromeda rescues us, we expose
its crew to contamination. We could take
it back to Earth."
&gt;&gt; What the hell are you suggesting?
&gt;&gt; We either send out a distress signal
or we send out a warning.
We tell the Andromeda to leave us here.
...
We can't let them land.
We have to make the sacrifice.
It's the right thing to do.
&gt;&gt; Directive 8020 doesn't stop us from
going back into orbit. I have faith in
Earth's quarantine procedures.
&gt;&gt; If we get back to Earth,
&gt;&gt; isn't that why we're here in the first
place?
&gt;&gt; Please think about what you're doing.
...
We can't risk endangering the Andromeda,
let alone Earth. We should tell them to
avoid this planet. We'll send a warning
to the Andromeda.
...
So, how much did you know?
&gt;&gt; As much as you
&gt;&gt; really
nothing.
&gt;&gt; Have I ever lied to you?
&gt;&gt; This would be a hell of a good reason
for a first time.
&gt;&gt; Young, I promise you, I knew nothing
before you did.
As far as I'm aware,
everyone was kept in the dark. For this
to work, no one could know.
...
We put in years of training.
We put our lives on the line. And now
this,
it's not fair.
&gt;&gt; It's the same end goal, young.
It's just that the objectives have
changed.
...
&gt;&gt; Do you think it will work?
&gt;&gt; Ours is not to reason why. There's
always someone above you in the chain of
command, Young. We don't always have the
details, but we have to trust those
above us to make the right call.
...
Young,
you're the last hold out.
For this to succeed, you need to sign.
Without you, years of work will have
been wasted.
&gt;&gt; If I agree to this,
it changes everything.
It's not just 8 years that will be lost.
...
I keep wondering,
am I condemning myself forever?
Whatever decision you make, know that
I'll stand by your side. I always have.
But you need to decide now.
...
Make sure you have each other's backs
and come back in one piece. I'll let you
know if anything comes in from Earth,
but until then, it's all on you.
...
Woo! That's one ticked off the bucket
list.
...
Keep your eyes on the drone.
We won't get back up this way. We'll
have to come in through the lower
airlock.
...
Man, this makes Earth look like a spa
tree.
...
Just think, we're the first humans to
step foot on an exoplanet.
&gt;&gt; We just keep making history today.
...
&gt;&gt; Hello, brave new world.
&gt;&gt; Whoa.
...
That could have been bad. The storm
doesn't look like it's going to let up
anytime soon.
&gt;&gt; Anders, from a scientist's point of
view,
&gt;&gt; do you think this planet could still be
our future home?
&gt;&gt; It's not impossible.
There's water, gravity.
The fact there's life here proves it.
Just a shame that
...
please,
please get off me.
...
Anders,
&gt;&gt; where the hell did she go?
&gt;&gt; Anders, don't stray too far. Your body
is still recovering from exposure to the
cold. Do you hear me? You could wear
yourself out before we find you.
&gt;&gt; I can't hear you. What are you saying?
&gt;&gt; Damn it. We need to hurry.
...
I got a message from Anders.
&gt;&gt; What' you say?
...
&gt;&gt; Ander said she'll turn on her emergency
beacon.
&gt;&gt; I found the start of her trail.
...
Damn. No way through. Anders must have
gone through before the arch collapsed.
We'll have to find another way around.
...
You okay?
&gt;&gt; I thought I was going to
...
Can any of you hear me?
&gt;&gt; Please, I need help.
&gt;&gt; I can't stay here like this.
&gt;&gt; She must be within range. Come on. This
guy trail seems to split here.
&gt;&gt; I'll check in with Anders.
...
&gt;&gt; What the
&gt;&gt; Anders,
&gt;&gt; we need to hurry.
...
Anders.
&gt;&gt; Hey, it's okay.
...
&gt;&gt; I feel fine now. Must be because you're
back. Oh,
I guess that's good.
Let's keep moving then.
...
Look at those growths. The substance is
reaching out of the atmosphere. It's
splitting off into space.
...
&gt;&gt; Is that what hit our ship?
This planet is cursed.
...
Damn it. What is it? The STLB isn't
working.
&gt;&gt; I got this, man.
...
It's me.
Holy [__] You can't sneak up on people
like that.
&gt;&gt; I wasn't sure if you were okay over
there.
&gt;&gt; I'm okay.
&gt;&gt; Who knew the F in Ta F stood for [__]
...
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Uh, not funny. Sorry.
&gt;&gt; You can work on your timing.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, I could work on a whole lot of
things.
...
There's a solution to everything. The
difference is whether you see the
solution and go with it or if you choose
not to see it.
&gt;&gt; How the [__] do you remember all these
things?
&gt;&gt; I've not always been happy.
But I made a choice to change that.
I remember these things to remind myself
where I came from.
It reminds me
that I've come a long way.
&gt;&gt; That's far out.
&gt;&gt; So, remember it for your next life, huh?
...
&gt;&gt; Hey, Son, can you help me with this
thing?
&gt;&gt; Sure.
...
Yeah.
&gt;&gt; What's this?
&gt;&gt; I hope the damage isn't too bad.
&gt;&gt; Some parts are blown.
They're all standard modules.
You should look around and see if
there's any spares to replace them.
...
A place for everything. Everything in
its place.
...
Andromeda,
this is officer Young, pilot of the
Casiopia.
We have crash landed on tower city F and
sustained massive structural damage.
Our crash was caused by
contact with a hostile alien life form.
This planet
is not going to be our home anymore.
Theus mission is a failure.
The data that follows contains
everything we know about the entity.
Do not attempt rescue.
Tad back.
...
I know what you've done to us. You're a
bunch of sick [__]
...
This planet is alive. It's destroying us
one by one. I'm sending you on
coordinates now.
&gt;&gt; Please, you need to save us. Get us off
again.
&gt;&gt; Holy [__]
...
You need to get away from Talet again.
It's too late for me. But you can save
the Andromeda. I can't let you risk your
crew for me. Please turn around. Please.
...
It doesn't make sense.
Those ships,
they're all ours.
How is that possible?
&gt;&gt; We were the first here.
&gt;&gt; Then who did this?
...
&gt;&gt; Corinth.
They did send ships before us.
&gt;&gt; What do you mean?
&gt;&gt; They sent us
...
The probe has message locks.
Half a dozen of them.
All of them were of us.
This has happened before.
...
And we're not the original crew.
This is a [__] nightmare.
How in the living hell do we not know?
Honestly, somebody had to know. Was it
you, Anders?
Was this why you joined the crew so
close to launch?
It's too convenient that you were
brought in last minute. You You [__]
knew, didn't you?
...
Why is no one talking? Are Are you
serious? This is insane. Please just
leave me alone. And just
...
Critical warning. Oxygen saturation
level 60%.
&gt;&gt; And alternative air supply.
&gt;&gt; I said stop right there.
&gt;&gt; You knew, didn't you? You [__] knew.
You always knew about this clone [__]
and you didn't say [__] about it.
&gt;&gt; That's not true.
&gt;&gt; [__] Then why were you trying to
run out?
&gt;&gt; Shut up. Don't I don't trust any of you.
&gt;&gt; Oh god.
...
&gt;&gt; We have to go through it.
&gt;&gt; Very [__] careful.
...
Critical warning. Oxygen saturation
level 60%. Seek alternative air supply.
...
warning.
&gt;&gt; Oxygen saturation moving%.
&gt;&gt; We'll find another way around. Stay
safe, man. We'll be with you soon.
...
Critical warning. Oxygen saturation
level 60%. Seek alternative air supply.
...
Critical warning. Oxygen saturation
level 60%. Seek alternative air supply.
...
Critical warning. Oxygen saturation
level 60%. Seek alternative air supply.
...
Critical warning. Oxygen saturation
level 60%. Seek alternative air supply.
...
deck three. Science deck. Critical
warning. Oxygen saturation level 60%.
Seek alternative air supply.
...
You stay here. I'll check ahead.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
Don't get [__] killed.
...
&gt;&gt; Could you try and recount for me what
happened that night?
...
&gt;&gt; I got the call in orbit.
I was doing my nightly checks.
&gt;&gt; Take your time.
...
&gt;&gt; There were 1,200 people on that station
and the fire
it was spreading too fast to control.
...
unidentifiable
in geocience.
...
&gt;&gt; Door systems compromised.
Reconfiguration required.
...
Reconfiguration in progress. 40%.
&gt;&gt; Still out of power.
...
Reconfiguration in progress. 100%.
Door function overridden.
...
Young
&gt;&gt; Sarnon,
&gt;&gt; thank goodness you're alive. Let's go.
...
&gt;&gt; Wait, they've broken the scanner.
&gt;&gt; I'm not a [__] alien.
We should keep going.
...
Hello, young.
&gt;&gt; What's going on?
&gt;&gt; We have received a message from Earth.
Would you like to hear it?
&gt;&gt; Play the message.
&gt;&gt; As you wish.
I know this will be difficult to hear,
but if you're still out there, you
deserve the truth.
The government knows what's on that
planet. They've known since Corbus
beamed back its first report. They chose
to keep the life form a secret. Scrubbed
the survey report clean. Told Corinth to
carry on as planned.
Eley designed her ships. We all went
through training,
but nobody knew what they were really
planning.
...
When we got into those pods, they copied
our personalities,
our memories, and uploaded them to
synthetic bodies.
Your clones.
There is no Andromeda mission following
you. There's another Cassiopia. And
behind that, another. There's a chain of
ships out there in space with more to
follow until we fully understand the
entity.
a a program we all signed up to once we
learned the truth.
You're part of an experiment
to see how humans cope with alien
contact and to see how the life form
responds to us. With each cycle, Earth
learns more. We send new ships and we
tweak our teams for new scenarios.
Thanks to you, we're winning this war.
...
Stop it.
&gt;&gt; [__] liars.
&gt;&gt; Well, so much for confidentiality.
&gt;&gt; You son of a [__] You knew about this.
&gt;&gt; Of course I knew.
I've known since the probe first sent
its data back to Earth. The whole thing
was my idea.
Well,
the OG Williams's idea.
&gt;&gt; You think this is funny?
&gt;&gt; Far from it.
This is the most serious thing I've ever
done.
&gt;&gt; I was right not to trust you.
&gt;&gt; So, you're like us. You're a clone, too.
&gt;&gt; Of course. My original self would never
have risked his life out here. Trust me.
I'm afraid I can't trust you at all.
&gt;&gt; I suppose I owe you some answers.
...
&gt;&gt; Why the hell did you join up to this?
&gt;&gt; Somebody on board had to carry out
instructions from Earth. Somebody I
could trust.
&gt;&gt; So, you were acting dumb all this time.
&gt;&gt; What can I say?
I'm a good liar. Now you have the truth.
Warts in all.
The question is, what are you going to
do about it?
&gt;&gt; Play the rest of the tape.
...
Sweet dreams, everyone. See you in four
years.
&gt;&gt; I feel for you, man. Just a few hours
sleep and then you guys are up for four
years. Try not to kill each other. We
all have a vital part to play on this
ship. I'm grateful to be here with every
one of you.
&gt;&gt; It's an honor, sir.
&gt;&gt; See you on the other side.
...
Daddy, look at me. I'm flying. I'm a
spaceman. Never forget why you started.
...
This mission was it, you know.
Everything I trained for,
he was right there.
...
No, I won't. A sign. My feet will be
firmly on the ground for god knows how
long.
Who knows what state we'll be in then.
...
&gt;&gt; If what's out there is as bad as they
think,
it's safer to be here.
...
Why couldn't it have just been simple?
The real crew on the real mission.
&gt;&gt; This is what the real mission was
destined to be. We just didn't know it
until now.
&gt;&gt; Don't you think that's awful?
Everything we trained for was a lie.
...
&gt;&gt; Young, what do you think the other
versions of you would do?
You know yourself and they will too.
...
&gt;&gt; You're right.
I'm just not sure I'm making the right
choice.
&gt;&gt; No matter what you choose,
I'll respect it.
...
Honey, you could never let me down.
Never.
...
A reminder that curfew has been pushed
up by two hours, but rest assured, live
coverage will continue. Stay tuned here
on channel 22 to follow this historic
launch live from the comfort of your own
home.
...
We've just received your warning.
It was always a one-way trip, but your
bravery is
outstanding. The data you've sent has
opened up amazing opportunities for the
future.
...
What Corinth is doing, it's for the
right reasons. Mars is ruined. Earth is
dying. We need to win this war.
...
But if you're hearing this,
I want you to know that it's been for
something.
It was all worth it.
It's worth it every time.
...
So we just die for them like [__]
cattle.
&gt;&gt; It was always a risk that you would
learn the truth. You were not the first
crew to do so. There are protocols in
place that I can deploy to ease your
distress.
&gt;&gt; What protocols?
&gt;&gt; I am authorized to assist with safe cell
termination if you desire.
There will be no pain.
What do you know about pain?
&gt;&gt; You mean there's no way out of this?
&gt;&gt; Escape from the cycle is impossible.
I'm sorry.
...
&gt;&gt; How the hell did they clone us?
&gt;&gt; Young said something about the pots.
&gt;&gt; That's correct. The synthetic bodies you
are using now were grown using your own
DNA.
When your original selves entered the
pods, your memories were copied and
uploaded to these bodies.
In each cycle, as far as each crew
knows, they are flying off to Ta F for
the first time.
So many souls,
so many different versions of me,
all trying to get back to one person. We
are one and the same.
I am still me and I will find my way to
Mika.
...
&gt;&gt; So that's it. Finished.
It's over.
...
I saw it clear as day.
There's more than one Cassiopia on this
planet.
&gt;&gt; Corinth has sent the Cassiopia here
before
again and again with the same crew.
...
&gt;&gt; I don't understand
how it's impossible.
&gt;&gt; This can't be
can't be true.
&gt;&gt; Just another It doesn't make any sense.
...
Never
forget
where you started.
...
Hey,
you still thinking of feeding me to the
plants when I die?
&gt;&gt; I don't know, man.
Do clones even have souls?
&gt;&gt; Probably not.
All I know is if there's a real Mitchell
out there who agreed to this plan, he's
a jerk.
Takes one to know one.
...
&gt;&gt; You see that?
&gt;&gt; It's got to be the pister ring.
...
&gt;&gt; What?
the booster ring.
&gt;&gt; Uh, yeah, that's what we're looking at.
&gt;&gt; It's got air, emergency supplies.
&gt;&gt; Okay, Hawking. Problem is, we need a
spaceship to get to it. The Cassiopia
isn't going anywhere.
&gt;&gt; What about the SUV? If we can dock the
ring,
&gt;&gt; we'll go nowhere. We'll be stuck up
there in space in a shuttle,
which is better than down here.
...
This cycle is over. You need to get your
head around that.
...
&gt;&gt; I'd rather not just kick back and wait
to die. Thanks, though.
You're not dying. You're not even
living. You're a tool.
You're a savior of the human race. And
though this body will die, your legacy
will grow with every cycle. I'm staying
here to fulfill my destiny.
...
Okay, then die here. I don't care.
&gt;&gt; Very well. I'll be in my office enjoying
a nice 18-year-old scotch and I'll raise
a glass to you all. It's been a pleasure
serving with you on this cycle.
...
Warnings. Manual override required.
&gt;&gt; What?
No. For God's sake.
We have to go back down.
&gt;&gt; The only way to get fuel up here is to
manually reroute it through the science
deck, then pump it up from all the way
down in bloody engineering.
I'm going to go down there and get this
done.
...
The [__]
system malfunction.
&gt;&gt; God [__] damn it.
&gt;&gt; Protocol initiated two. Manual.
...
We're not going anywhere till this is
unblocked
...
&gt;&gt; That's where we need to go.
&gt;&gt; Got it.
&gt;&gt; Let's get this done.
...
Can you hear me?
&gt;&gt; God damn it. Is this thing even working?
&gt;&gt; Mitchell,
&gt;&gt; I'm not going to let you die out there.
...
This is going to be tricky. Don't get
too close.
...
Eat [__]
&gt;&gt; We don't have time for this. Let's keep
going.
&gt;&gt; Threats alive. Seek alternative air
supply immediately.
...
[__] sake.
&gt;&gt; No. No. No. No. No. No,
&gt;&gt; Cooper.
...
We don't have time for this. Let's keep
going.
...
What the hell was that?
&gt;&gt; Whatever it was,
it sounded big.
...
Wow.
6 months.
&gt;&gt; Has it really been that long?
&gt;&gt; I've never known something to go by so
quickly and so slowly all at once. Let's
see.
...
Malfunction resolved. Lockdown has been
lifted.
...
Fuel cell critically unstable. Urgent
depressurization required.
...
Threats alert. Seek alternative air
supply immediately.
...
threats alive. Seek alternative air
supply immediately.
...
Threats alive. Seek alternative air
supply immediately.
...
threats alive. Seek alternative air
supply immediately.
...
The rat's alive.
Seek alternative air supply immediately.
...
&gt;&gt; I've been a bit up and down the last few
days. Haven't really been sleeping much.
I've been going over it all in my head.
Trying to see if I'm making this up.
But honestly, it doesn't matter if I
believe it or not. Carter was right.
This isn't healthy.
...
There are some places here that give me
peace.
...
If I sit there and close my eyes,
I can almost picture you sitting next to
me.
...
I was this close to getting wrapped up
in it all,
but
I'm okay now.
...
I'm going to channel my energy into
getting back on top of that leaderboard.
...
Carter says I get my stubbornness from
you.
I miss you. Well,
...
&gt;&gt; [__]
&gt;&gt; warning. Your systems compromised. Alter
Protocol initiated.
Unidentifiable organic.
...
Threats alive. Seek alternative air
supply immediately.
...
Reactor overloaded. Impending meltdown
in 10 minutes. Please evacuate to
safety.
...
Reactor overloaded. Impending meltdown
in 5 minutes. Please evacuate to safety.
...
Hey, it's me. You got to let me in.
They're right behind me. Open the
[__] door.
...
&gt;&gt; I'm sorry about what happened before.
What I did,
but you you can't leave me out here.
Please.
...
[__] you.
Fuel level is at 95%.
&gt;&gt; We need to launch now.
&gt;&gt; Target locked.
...
What happens now?
&gt;&gt; We keep holding on.
We've made it this far.
...
I dreaming?
Take it easy, young. It takes a few
minutes for the body to adjust to wake
up. Vitals are looking good. Oxygen
saturation 95%.
&gt;&gt; Everything seems to be in working order.
If you don't mind, please look up for
me.
Excellent. That should do it.
...
&gt;&gt; Good morning.
Looks like you could use one of these.
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Sims.
...
Looks like we're on schedule. We're
right on top of the marker.
...
&gt;&gt; Sure is.
&gt;&gt; You ever think what you might have been
if you weren't a pilot?
&gt;&gt; Not a chance. This has always been it
for me.
&gt;&gt; Goddamn right.
I could do this forever.
...
&gt;&gt; My only goal is to ensure a successful
mission and the safe return of my crew.
That's my job. But if I had any skin in
this game, it would be to get this crew
home safely so we can get you to your
new home.
If this mission fails,
&gt;&gt; it could spell the end for the human
race.
&gt;&gt; And I'm not going to let that happen.
...
&gt;&gt; I considered applying for the Andromeda
mission, but until I have a family of my
own, those five rug rats playing ball
and seti.
Until then, I'm sticking with Stafford
and Young. That's my family right there.
And that means more to me than all the
planets in the galaxy.
&gt;&gt; Corinth is going to make Tower City F
our new home. We don't know exactly what
we're going to find there, but we have
the technology and the ingenuity to turn
that world around.
Science can't solve all of our problems,
but it can give us the questions we need
to answer.
...
&gt;&gt; I wish you all eight wonderful
Christmases.
I only hope that we can return to
deliver you and your families the very
best Christmas present of all
&gt;&gt; a new world.
...
&gt;&gt; There's no room for human error.
Ultimately, if something goes wrong
because of the design, that's on me. If
we fail, it's because I have failed.
...
People everywhere have tough times and
now more people than ever before are
facing something terrible.
&gt;&gt; I want to bring them hope.
&gt;&gt; We all need a little hope.
&gt;&gt; But also because of its purpose and
despite the distance and duration, it
will make me feel closer to humanity
somehow.
&gt;&gt; The oneness of it all. You know,
&gt;&gt; everything is going to be okay.
Things can only get better.
...
&gt;&gt; I've always wanted to fly.
&gt;&gt; The joy of it, the freedom of it to just
take your life in your hands and soar.
&gt;&gt; I think that's in us all, isn't it? At
least that's what my dad taught me.
Um, but there's more to it than that.
When dad took off for Mars, he told me
the whole crew looked back at Earth and
pointed to which country they came from.
As they traveled further, they pointed
to each continent they were from.
&gt;&gt; Finally,
&gt;&gt; they just saw one Earth.
&gt;&gt; That's always given me hope for us all.
...
backlight shimmer.
A steady heavy in the mind
and I don't want to say
we are the road to nowhere
to circle nothing.
...
Do you know?
Do you know who you are
truly?
You can know
with your heart
...
Do you know who you are
truly?
Do you know
with your whole heart?
...
When faced with oblivion,
humanity, like all life, must adapt.
To conquer the unknown, we must weigh
who we are and be prepared to lose it
all.
...
Cycle 13 was a significant milestone for
the program. For the first time, the
life form intercepted the Cassiopia
outside orbit.
...
The clone crew survived the crash and
managed to broadcast a message.
It was a warning. Despite everything
that happened, they put humanity first.
On my orders, Williams deployed a neural
control compound onto the planet
surface, but it failed to establish
control over the life form.
Given more cycles, this could become a
viable path.
...
Williams executed the directive without
any of the crew noticing.
...
As for the crew themselves,
three souls escaped the planet surface.
...
They sought refuge in the Cassiopia's
booster ring. Better to die in space
than fall victim to their life form.
...
Never forget why you started.
I joined this project because I believed
it would secure the future of humanity.
The more we learned about the life form,
the greater our chances of survival.
If it could be sculpted into a tool to
save humanity,
then I had a duty to actualize this.
It's a strange word, isn't it? Humanity.
On one hand, it's a definition of us as
a species. On the other, kindness,
compassion,
even love, attributes we've all but
forgotten.
Our fight for survival should never come
at the cost of our humanity.
We can no longer hide behind clones. If
we ever hope to master death, we must
first stare it in the face. All of us
together.